Heat. Heat.
Heat. Heat. N.
Heat.
Welcome Living Mana Church family. It's
so good to have you here with us today
worshiping on this Sabbath day. So good
to see you guys. Please put in the chat
where you are viewing from. We want to
say a special welcome to you and you
guys know the rules. If you're just
visiting for the first time, and maybe
if you're the first time, you don't know
the rules, but the others know the
rules. If it's your first time, please
put a one in the chat. We want to say a
special welcome to you and just let you
know a little bit more about Living Mana
Online Church. But we're excited to have
you all here. We know this is a very
even though today is the Sabbath and
we're so thankful for the rest that the
Sabbath brings. This is still a very
busy time of year just because it's the
holiday season. Some of you may have
already started traveling. Uh but we're
just so happy that you are here with us
today. Um and you're worshiping with us
here at Living Mana Church. We are
definitely uh happy to be live, happy to
be with you, uh happy that you are
joining us in this worship service and
uh we believe that God always has
something special
>> always.
>> Um you know with these living manner
services, our Sabbath schools um you
know we deal with very practical things.
>> Oh yes. and this um this series we're
doing on the Christian art of war
>> dealing with how to overcome uh you know
battles against yourself daily struggles
>> um so we uh we attempt to speak
relevance uh to address issues that are
relevant to your everyday life to your
walk with Christ so um if you're joining
us for the first time um you know we we
pray that our this service will speak to
you personally.
>> Yes. Want to say welcome and um happy
Sabbath back to Mac Boaz or should I say
Feliz Sabado. Back to you. Um also to
John um um Heasley from MacArthur, Ohio.
Always good to see you here. Uh John um
all right let's see. You said okay MacB
you said happy Sabbath. Well Fel Sabado
and that and so but you're watching from
Kansas. So, welcome Wendy from Idaho
Falls. Good to see you here. So thankful
that you are here with us here at Living
Mana Church. Barbara from Anguila, great
to see you. And yes, please continue to
put in the chat where you guys are
viewing from. And again, if this is your
first time visiting with Living Mana uh
Church, please put a one in the chat so
we can see uh that you're here for the
first time, but also where you um are
viewing from as well.
Yes. So good again to see all of you
here.
>> So, um, we, uh,
>> um,
I was actually going to bring up what
you said, not to bring up.
>> I know you so well. So, yes, I I know
him so well.
>> Um, all right.
>> But we are, uh, like I said, we we're
excited about the Sabbath school today.
Um we're going to be we're going to be
continuing on in the Christian
>> uh art of war dealing with the fruit of
the spirit.
>> Yes.
>> Um and
>> it's goodness.
>> Yeah, we're on goodness.
>> Goodness today. Yes, we're excited for
that. To let you guys know, those of you
who do not ha have not are just visiting
for the first time or have not gotten uh
the the um the book. I mean, you can't
get the book, but we we're releasing
chapter by chapter of the book, The
Christian Art of War, which pastor Myers
wrote about 15 years ago. You can go on
Mighty Networks, and there you will be
able to get each chapter. Four four
chapters have been released because
we're still on chapter 4. We are going
so incredibly slow, but it's been such a
blessing the things that we are all um
being are reading and talking about here
on Sabbath morning. Um let's see. I also
want to say welcome from not sure the
name but from Grand Rapids, Michigan.
Good to see you here. Uh we have Lina uh
from Brooklyn, New York. Good to see you
here. Heidi from Virginia. Welcome to
Living Mana Church.
Let's see. We have um I'm not sure the
name, but it's from Vancouver Island,
Canada, which one of our board members
is in Vancouver Island, too. I thought
that was Jod at first, but then it was a
different name. So, welcome. Welcome
here to Living Manage Church. It's good
to have you here worshiping with us. All
right, I think as you guys continue. All
right, we have Robert um in Seattle.
Beautiful Seattle with um I almost said
Mount Hood, but that's in Portland or in
Oregon.
>> Um Mount Reneer is the one that we see
in Seattle. Welcome. Here we have
Atlanta, Georgia. Good to see you here.
Thank you for um joining us here at
Living Mana Church. You guys continue to
put in the chat where you're viewing
from. And again, if this is your first
time, please put a one. And I think I'm
going to go to t-shirt messages.
>> Uh faith
does not make things easy, it makes them
possible.
>> Yes. And as I was praying and thinking
like what t-shirt is for today, Lord,
this is so um just right on time. I
literally had to explain this concept to
a good friend this week because I my
prayer you guys have heard me talk about
her before, but my prayer mentor um
Janet Paige and she was uh my uh
president's wife at the conference uh
the first conference that we uh that he
pastored in. and she was such a blessing
um to all of the pastor's wives. Like
the things she taught us is just like
amazing. But
>> she was like the first person um where I
would call her and be like, you know,
I'm going through this or this is
happening and blah. She was really a
friend. She was a friend to all of us.
It was just amazing.
>> And so um and she was like the first
person that said, "Okay, she wouldn't
even let me get that far into the
story." Like literally like like early
like just the little just right at the
beginning. and she'd be like, "Okay,
let's praise God now." I'm like,
>> "Janet, I'm like basically crying and I
want to just pour out my all of my
problems." She's like, "Let's praise
him. Let's praise him right now. We're
going to praise him in the midst of the
storm, basically." And so, um, I was
able to share that concept with a friend
this week and I was thinking like, I
feel like Janet and she feels like how I
probably felt like, okay, yeah, right.
You know, it's almost like a little
annoying when somebody says that when
you're in the midst of something and it
first hits. Um, but it's true. Um, and
this is what like faith, we can have
faith. It doesn't mean that it's that
it's easy.
>> Yeah.
>> And it it just made me think of what I
tell my clients when I have them do
affirmations because I the affirmations
are positive things you're telling
yourself because you're always we have
negative selft talk that has been going
on like
>> like a like a
>> I was going to say like a t like a
repeat. I don't know. They don't know
what tape. Well, young people don't know
what take anyway when things are like on
repeat, right?
>> Yeah.
>> So, it's just like repeat repeat the in
the the negative stuff. So, it's just
like, you know, tell yourself the
positive stuff, but when you tell
yourself the positive things at first,
>> you feel like you're lying to yourself.
You feel it feels awkward and it's
weird. Yeah.
>> But I'm like, I don't care. Push. I This
is what I tell my clients. I don't care
how it feels. You just keep saying it
and keep doing it until it's then it's
going to start to feel normal and
natural.
>> It's the same thing with the faith in
the situation. Like when Janet used to
tell me that, I'd be like, "Okay, let's
pray." And then we'd praise God. Like I
still felt a certain kind of way about
the situation.
>> But after a while, my feelings changed
because my my thoughts and what I was
saying was changing.
>> Repetition.
>> Repetition the impression.
>> Yes. So when you're in a situation, have
faith even when you don't feel like it.
Um you're not gonna you're praising God.
Have faith and you're going to praise
God through it. And you're not
necessarily going to feel it,
>> but
it makes things possible because you're
going to believe it. I mean, you're
going to believe it even though you
don't see it or feel it, but eventually
it's going to come.
>> Amen.
>> So,
>> amen.
>> Yes, that is our message for today.
All right.
>> And uh so I think we are
>> ready for I mean I was talking so much I
might have missed Yeah, I don't think I
missed a one. I just saw uh
I don't know what country this is. I
don't know what flag that is. Kind of
looks like Italy though. I think that
looks like Italy. I just want to say a
greeting. I saw a different country that
I wasn't
>> in Doha, but it says Doha, but the flag
looks like Italy. But maybe not.
Well, happy Sabbath to happy Sabbath
from um you're there in Doha. So, happy
Sabbath and welcome here to Living Man
Church. And I missed Oklahoma. Oh, and
Australia. Welcome. Welcome from
Australia. It is.
>> Amen.
>> Sunday morning
>> over there. Good to see you here.
>> All right.
>> We are ready to start.
>> We're gonna uh
>> pray.
>> Go ahead and pray and then invite our
guests on.
>> Yes.
>> So, um let's let's do that now. Heavenly
Father,
>> we come before you, Lord, thanking you
uh for this um this Sabbath, Lord.
thanking you for this day of rest.
Thanking you for a time that we can come
together and fellowship, Lord. And Lord,
thanking you for the technology that
allows us to do this from around the
world, even though we're we're all in
different places, Lord.
>> Um and so, Lord, as we um begin this
Sabbath school today and continue our
discussion on the Christian art of war,
Lord, please bless our conversation and
uh may everything that is said be
uplifting and glorifying, Lord, to you.
And uh may those who listen and watch um
walk away with a greater understanding,
Lord, of what it means to walk in your
way. In Jesus name we pray. Amen.
>> Amen.
Amen. So we want to welcome our Sabbath
school panel.
All right. We'll see you guys in just
There you are. Welcome.
Good to see you guys. And yes, I Okay.
Have you ever been surprised live on the
air? Because I'm surprised right now.
Welcome, welcome, welcome, welcome to to
Terry and to Kashif and Melinda. Good to
see you.
>> And Karen.
>> And Karen. I Hi, Karen.
>> Karen, can you hear us?
>> Okay.
>> Okay. Welcome. It's good to have you
here for Sabbath School. And the reason
why I said surprised, I just wasn't I
didn't know Karen was gonna be here and
that's why I didn't say your name
because I really Yeah, I wasn't sure who
that was up in the square. But welcome
Karen. It's great to have you. Great to
have you here for Sabbath school to talk
to talk about the Christian art of war.
And along with everyone else, so good to
see you guys. All right, so did you want
to
>> So what we're gonna do
>> Okay.
>> Um let's see. We left off on uh the
fruit of
gentleness.
>> I was going to say gentleness, but I
just didn't want to say the wrong. I
think it's gentleness.
>> Gentleness.
>> And we are now going to be um looking at
Let me let me get this up here. We're
going to be looking at um
>> All right. The spirit of goodness. The
spirit of goodness.
And um I'm going to go ahead guys and
read I'm going to read the whole
segment. Okay. And then which actually
this one is not that long. So it's a few
paragraphs.
>> So we may be able to do gentleness and
faith in this session.
>> All right.
>> So let's see how it goes. We'll start
off with with uh the spirit of goodness.
>> All right. So uh the spirit of goodness
is the spirit of virtue and honor. The
warrior of Christ is to be bound by a
code of honor. The world is fast losing
its moral compass. Many do what is right
in their own sight. Good is being called
evil and evil is being called good. The
distinction between right and wrong are
nearly extinguished. It is in this very
time that the spirit of goodness is
needed the most.
It is a lost chivalry of Christianity.
The warrior must be a good warrior. Be
good at what you do. Paul said, "I have
fought a good fight. I have finished my
course. I have kept the faith." 2
Timothy 4:7.
We are not to settle for mediocre
results. Whatsoever thy hand finds to
do, do it with thy might.
We are constantly we are to constantly
seek to better our warfare.
This spirit of not settling for anything
but the best in spiritual things is
another necessity for the Christian
warrior. Not only should a warrior be
good at what he does, but he must also
be good at who he is. Therefore, if any
man be in Christ, he's a new creature.
All old things are passed away. Behold,
all things are become new.
Being born again, the warrior for Christ
is a new creature possessing the fruit
or offspring of the spirit. His
character and who he and who he is um
his character and who he is given to him
is given to him through the spirit of
Christ. He is to be good at love, good
at joy,
good at peace, good at patience.
>> In all that we say and do, the spirit of
goodness is to have control. Virtue and
honor, for Christ's sake, must become an
unbending rule. In ancient in
ancient Japan, a warrior's honor was of
utmost importance. He was willing to
save it even unto death. The Christian
warrior can be no different.
>> He must be willing to He must be rather
willing. He must be willing rather to
die than betray Jesus. Death before
dishonor was the ancient code of honor
for first century Christians.
>> Revelation 12:11 says, "They overcame
him by the blood of the lamb and by the
word of their testimony, and they love
not their lives unto the death."
>> Uh, so it must be.
So it must be for us in our battle
against self. Only then can we fight a
good fight.
>> Amen. Amen.
>> So
how do we
fight the good fight of faith? Um how do
we learn to be good
uh at
walking the Christian walk?
How do we learn to be good
at
love, patience,
>> mercy,
kindness?
>> What are your thoughts?
>> Like anything else, practice.
>> Practice. And I'll never forget what Kia
said several weeks ago. the foundation
has to be love for all of these fruits.
>> Um
to to be effective and for us to um
actually implement them in our life and
to become natural, you have to have that
fruit of love. So through practice and
having that foundation of love,
>> will goodness come?
>> Uh all right, we're going to open the
floor.
>> Yes.
>> I mean the floor is already open, but
>> please jump in your thoughts on what we
have. uh what we have uh spoken so far.
>> I really like what first lady said where
she was pointing back to what Kazia
said. Um and she was talking about how
um we need to have love before we can
have all the other fruits of the spirit.
I mean it's a biblical principle we have
for we loved because he first loved us.
So I think that's true.
We love him because he first
loved us. Uh, and you're saying that
that love is what precedes everything
else. And how do you tie that in with
goodness?
>> You can't have goodness without love.
you're you're not going to
um
like I always think about Joseph when he
was tempted um
>> and he's like how could I do this sin
against my father because he had love u
he would be able to do the good practice
goodness because of the foundation of
love
>> towards God.
>> Yeah. Um, I think,
uh,
you know, I don't know if anybody's ever
been in a fight.
Um,
>> I've never been in a fight.
>> So, you know, for me,
>> in a physical fight,
>> uh, well, a good fight was always a
fight that you won. A bad fight was the
fight that you lost. The fight you
didn't want to talk about. You didn't
want to tell, you know, you just didn't
want to discuss it. a good fight you're
always like man you know this this
happened this is back in the world right
so
when Paul says fight the good fight of
faith I think there you know in a sense
the good fight of faith means that's the
fight that we win
>> right that's the fight that we uh that
we
um
that we come out on top
and
you know the more you win fights the
better you feel about fighting.
>> The more you lose fights is the more you
is the closer you get to wanting to give
up.
>> So
I think it is
we have to get into the we have to learn
what it means to like
>> uh have winning streaks, right?
when you have winning streaks. Oh, you
know, I'm on a I'm on a streak. I think
we talked about it last week. Being in
the flow,
right? Being in the flow.
>> Um,
>> yeah,
>> talked about that. Okay. Um, so how do
we fight
and gain victory
after victory after victory
and then
every victory we gain helps us to
understand, hey, I can do this in
Christ, right?
>> I can do all things through Christ which
strengthens me. Um,
I think that
walk that that that
streak of winning
>> is what Paul is addressing when he says,
"Fight the good fight of faith." Don't
fight a bad fight.
>> Fight a good fight.
>> Every victory helps you
mentally and emotionally for the next
time.
>> Yeah. Even though it's going to be
you're gonna when that temptation comes,
you're going to be back in the fight,
but you have that spiritual um memory
>> that I've done this before. I've I've
won before.
>> I've I've beat this before.
>> Yeah. And then after time, I truly
believe after time, that thing that
you're trying to have victory in after a
significant amount of time,
>> that isn't a temptation anymore, right?
>> But you're on to new things. God is
working on on you. You know, we just
never arrive
>> to perfection.
>> Yeah.
>> Um but God is working on a new thing
with you. Yeah.
>> That you're learning how to fight and to
win.
>> Yeah.
>> Amen. Um
Well, I hate to chime in right when we
start talking about fighting, but that
that is uh you're hitting on my stuff
now. Really uh I love what you were
saying earlier, first lady, about um
your praise your prayer mentor who
taught you about praising in the middle
of the storm
>> and and we're talking about fighting.
You know, a good fight. I remember when
I was teaching um men's purity groups
and I was telling them just because you
got hit doesn't mean that the fight is
over and just because you got hit
doesn't mean that you lost. And so in
the same sense that hey I put together
some victories and I've won some fights.
Well, I've also been hit before. So they
I I know how to take a punch and keep
going. And I know that punch doesn't
necessarily mean hey God's not in it.
And so I was sharing with the uh prayer
team this morning in the huddle because
I was thinking about goodness and what
pastor said in his book and the Lord
reminded me of Moses. And he says,
"Look, show me your glory." And the Lord
says, "Well, I will make all my goodness
pass before you, but you're not going to
be able to see my face." And when we're
in the middle of a trial, that's what we
want to see. We want to know, God,
you're here. You you you know I'm in
trouble and you're here to help. And and
God put Moses in. He said, "I'll put you
in this place over here in the and you
can see my hind parts."
>> So, a lot of times for me when I'm in
the middle of a mess, I don't
necessarily I can't discern God all the
time, but I can always look back. Oh, he
was there from behind, right? And so,
I'm learning this thing about praising
him in the middle of the storm. So, I
thank I thank God for what you were
saying this morning about praising him
because his goodness is not there. It's
there. Just got to get used to seeing it
recognize.
>> Yeah.
>> Yeah. You know, I was thinking about the
story of uh
uh David and Goliath
and um I I will say it this way that
David wasn't afraid to fight Goliath
because he had had some good fights in
the past,
right?
Um, he fought against a lion, he fought
against a bear, and those were good
fights.
>> Yeah.
>> And I think good fights help prepare us
>> for bigger fights in the future.
>> Um,
so
when David is getting ready to fight
Goliath, he's looking back at the fight
with the lion. He's looking back at the
fight with the bear, right? And when we
have those winds under our belts, right,
it reminds us, hey, not this is what I
did, but this is what God did,
right? This is what God did for me. This
is what God did through me. So if you
did it then, he can do it now. And I
think that idea of the good fight is is,
you know,
>> it is
It is crucial.
And Terry, you were talking about uh you
talking about Jacob just now.
>> Terry, were you talking
>> Who are you talking about with the
>> Moses?
>> Moses.
>> Oh, you know,
>> I think it's 33.
>> Yeah, Exodus 33. When he was saying, um,
>> yes,
>> I'll go, but I need you I need to know
you're with me, Lord, or I'm not going
anywhere. That's pretty much what he was
saying. And he said, "Well, show me your
glory. This I'll do this thing you've
asked me to do. However, no one can see
my face and live."
>> So he put him in the cliff of the rock.
He says, "I'll make my goodness pass
before you." Goodness,
>> but you know, and so he saw his
backside. He didn't see the front, you
know, it was his goodness pass. He saw
him as he went by. And I thought, "Wow,
that's interesting
>> concept for me that in the middle of my
trial, even though the goodness is
there, sometimes it looks like something
I can't look upon. I can't see it and
until retrospect a lot and how I hold up
in the middle of the fight is whether or
not I can discern the fact God your
goodness is here. It is here. I just may
not discern it until
later when I'm giving my testimony of
how awesome you were in the middle of it
and it had nothing to do with me.
>> Yeah. Yeah. That's the true walk of
faith that I don't even feel. I mean,
that's what Jesus held on to on the
cross. It's just
>> I just have to believe because he didn't
feel the presence
>> of God was was gone.
>> And that's when he cried out.
>> Yeah.
>> But he still he still didn't come down.
>> And I feel he didn't denounce God
>> like you left me. Somebody take me down
off this cross.
>> No, he didn't say that. Go ahead, Terry.
Yeah, I just want to make a confession
this, you know, and just being honest. I
would rather just go through life with
no problems,
>> no mess, no drama, no trials,
>> none of that, right?
>> But how would I know how good God is if
I don't get in that stuff and watch him
bring me out? If I don't watch him
provide for I'm doing without. I don't
watch him come through and show me his
goodness, you know, uh, in the middle of
a a mess when I know I don't deserve
anything. And a lot of times, God has
shown me that, hey, I'm allowing all
this to happen so that you can manifest
what I'm working in you.
>> My goodness to be shown in the in these
situations.
>> Yeah.
>> In these fights.
>> Sometimes
>> I think that's also Sorry.
>> Go. No, go ahead.
>> Okay. I think that's also a reason why
um in heaven when we read in Revelation,
I forget which chapter it is, but in
Revelation where the redeemed um sing
the song of the lamb and you know only
they can tell how the song of Moses
they're singing and only they can tell
how good God is because they've been
through it all
>> and everybody else all the angels and
stuff they can't really relate to it
because they haven't been through what
we are what we've been through and
exactly what brother Terry said about
well I'd like to live without trials but
then How would I know how good God is?
>> Absolutely.
>> Yeah. Um I think
that
the way that we become good fighters, I
think you have to train with the best
>> and that's how you become a good
fighter.
Um, and when you train with the best,
uh, I think the the evidence that you
have trained with the best is when is
when you walk with a limp.
>> So, Jacob,
>> I was going to say that's why you
thought it was Jacob was on that.
>> That's why I was hearing Jacob when you
were saying Moses.
>> Your mind was thinking he was.
>> I was like, man, Terry got there before
me, too.
>> I was just hearing this. But Jacob, he
practiced with God,
>> right?
>> He wrestled with God. So man, if I can
wrestle with God and walk and walk away
from that alive,
then
you're just a person,
>> right? You're just a person that
you I'm not afraid of you. And this is
not afraid of like I'll fight you, but
I'm saying afraid in in a sense of I
will not fear what man can do unto me.
>> Because Jacob in wrestling with God
>> uh would not let go
>> and
um he fought a good fight.
>> Yes.
And that fight for us happens in prayer.
>> We wrestle in prayer
>> with God. I mean we talk and it's when
we say wrestle it sounds like so
>> uh violent
>> but emotionally it is sometimes I mean
when you know we're crying out to God
we're quite you know what we're hearing
him speak to us you know to our hearts
and uh but it's a wrestle but that's
where that is happening.
>> Yeah. And
and even when we come out of prayer, I
mean, we've trained, we've learned, and
then as we go throughout our day and
that issue that we were wrestling with
God with, you know, comes before us,
that's still
a wrestle, but you train so you it's not
a it's an easier wrestle, if you will.
>> May not feel when temptation comes feel
so easy at first, but you've trained
>> Yeah. with God. So you can you can
execute what the master taught you to do
in those situations.
>> Amen.
>> Can we can we talk about Jacob one more
time?
>> Um I don't know how many of you saw
this, have seen this, or you can
remember it. I I I would strongly
encourage you go look it up. I was still
in on vacation when I first saw this
video. Pastor was preaching. Uh I I I
don't he may have been preaching in
Jamaica and in that testimony he was
talking about the way he used to walk
and he we had this thing we call a
stroll or a flop you know we had that
little walk almost like music was
playing so pastor actually demonstrated
it and it it's it's interesting because
>> you want to demonstrate it for us here
>> I don't think I he demonstrated it's
that little that little walk that little
jazzy walk right and the guys I used
kind of run with. Everybody had that
little flop. Everybody had their own
thing. We call it a flop, right?
Everybody had their own flop.
>> And that that stroll represented
cockiness or, you know, I'm bad. Not
necessarily I'm practicing with the most
high and this is a limp. It shows I'm
leaning on him.
>> Yeah.
>> And so it was interesting that pastor
brought that out because when you after
walking with God, all that stuff starts
fading away. You know, you don't you
don't walk around like that anymore.
>> Yeah. I remembered it when he said.
>> Yeah. But it's funny because I was
thinking about the same thing, Terry.
>> I was like, yeah, it's a different limp
when you're when you're like, "Yeah, I
wrestle with God."
>> Yeah.
>> What? What's up?
>> What?
>> What? Right.
>> And it's uh
it's that walk of humility versus where
in the world
>> it's the walk of pride.
>> Yeah.
>> Absolutely. Because um
Jacob's limp
was I mean man what a thing. Why is he
limping like that? He wrestled with God.
>> Wait what?
>> Like imagine the the the the uh
just the
spiritual fame
that comes with that.
>> Yeah. that that man wrestled with God
and he's
>> and came out alive.
>> Came out alive.
>> Came out alive,
>> you know, and and and think about
>> Can I just suggest, sorry, can I just
suggest that if Jesus if if okay, Jacob
wrestled with God and he came out alive,
usually if you think, okay, somebody
comes out alive, well,
was this like a like a training fight or
like a fight to death? Because usually
you don't come out alive if if each
person really means it and it's like,
you know, I'm going to just like beat
you to the ground.
>> So him coming out alive is really a
testament to God's mercy in that
situation.
>> Yes.
>> Rather than to Jacob's resilience.
>> Yeah.
>> Right.
>> You know what I mean? I don't know.
>> No, no, no. That was that was Yeah.
>> Praise God. Amen.
>> Yeah,
>> that's a powerful insight.
>> Yeah, it's very powerful.
>> Melinda's what you just said reminds me
of uh what is it? Romans 4:2. says, "The
goodness of God leadth thee to
repentance."
>> Right? He wasn't necessarily trying to
beat me down to the ground in my
unwillingness. And I did deserve to be
beat all the way down. He showed me his
mercy and his goodness.
>> That's powerful.
>> Yeah. Very powerful, Melinda. Thank you.
And the wrestle, the reason why you can
come out alive because the wrestle is
really God trying to get you to let that
thing go. Like he can't whatever that
sin you're dealing with or whatever
you're dealing with to let it go. He he
cannot force us to let it go. We
actually have to choose to release even
though it's it's through his strength,
but sometimes we want to hold on to
things so long or we don't want to. Like
even if it's anger, even if it's uh
frustration of whatever the situation
is, he's we're like in the battle with
him wrestling. And his goal is to get us
to to let it go. And through that, uh we
come out alive and happy. Happier.
>> Yeah. and at peace. That's the Russell.
>> Kashif, I don't know if you were jumping
trying to say something a little bit
early. I thought I heard you.
>> Yeah, actually. Um, yeah.
>> Oh, sorry. Okay.
>> Okay, you guys hear me, right?
>> Yep.
>> Yeah. I was I was just coming back to,
you know, um, how do you get good at
being good at the fruits of the spirit,
right? And um for me my my my personal
thing is um we all have that that one
time or couple times where we could
truly remember overcoming by the spirits
of God. And um
I usually remember my thought process in
that moment. You know that that moment
where you're like oh man I can't afford
to allow this temptation to overcome me
again. And you know, you you have that
true that true surrender in that moment
and you're just like, you know what,
God, I really you need to to help me
with this.
>> And you know that you overcome that and
you move on to the next thing because no
doubt, you know, the temptations are
coming there. Yeah. The enemy is always
trying to bombard us, right?
>> Yeah.
>> And you have that sequence of
overcoming, you know, as pastor was
saying that you have that sequence of of
victories. And I always go back to the
exact thought process for each moment.
And that is like a it's almost like a
training sequence. Well, you did it
here. You did it here. You did it here.
But how did you do it? How did you
overcome? Because you surrendered in
every moment.
>> Moments where you know you want to you
want to argue, you want to shout, you
want to retaliate, and then you know you
just completely let it go. And Christ
was able to give you that particular
moment to overcome.
>> Yeah.
>> Amen.
Amen.
>> Yeah. There was I I was going to build
on something um
and tie that in and it just slipped my
mind. Um
man, it was right there.
>> You don't ever thought it was right
there.
>> Okay.
come back
to that vibe.
>> What about um up here where you said in
the book that the warrior of Christ is
to be bound by a code of honor.
>> Um
I love what you were saying, you know,
the distinction between good and evil
and evil and good. And I was meditating
on this yesterday and a couple days ago
um right in the middle of stuff. Um
it seems that
our
to manifest goodness and mercy towards
those who may not seem to deserve it
um doesn't seem to be the way uh things
are. It's certainly not the way things
are going in the world. And it makes you
wonder whether or not the God have
confidence in goodness that it will
overcome evil. Good will always overcome
evil. Do we have faith in God's way of
doing things and that his power and his
his character will eventually prevail.
And you you guys know about a situation
I was going through and I didn't tell a
whole lot of people about it, but
in that moment, God gave me the grace to
give him an opportunity to show his
goodness. And then just a few days later
because of that,
>> I got a big old hug from the person that
I was ready to show some badness,
>> but I did
>> and he heard about something was going
through and just came and gave me a big
old hug
>> and thanked God for it because in that
moment he was giving me an opportunity
to to show that my way does work and
it's it's not all about you, it's about
somebody else,
>> you know, and
So, um, I'm just thinking, you know,
Lord, help us with this whole idea of
not flipping it around and thinking that
the evil way of doing things is always
the best way of doing things,
>> right?
>> Yeah.
>> And, uh, get our moral compass together.
>> Really?
>> Yeah.
>> Um,
how do we fight? How do we learn? What
is the good fight of faith? Um,
I think about the story of Jacob
wrestling with God and imagine God
saying to you,
"Get off of me.
Let me go."
and and not in a let me go Jacob, but in
the middle of a fight,
God is telling you let him go.
>> And you know, I don't know
like if I if we're to hear those words
from God spoken to us personally, let go
of me.
>> I mean, that's a command.
>> Yeah.
>> Right. That's a command.
and and think about the the uh
the desperation of Jacob
>> where he's like, "I know who you are and
I know you've told me to to let go of
you.
I'm not
>> letting go." Now, how are you fighting
against the God of the universe and
telling the God of the of the uni
knowing that the God of the universe
cannot just make you let go but simply
disappear you
>> to where you just cease to exist
>> instantly
>> and
Jacob says no
I will not obey your command. and
to let you go.
>> I will do anything else. I'm not doing
that. I will not let you go. And it kind
of reminds you of the story of Abraham,
right?
>> Where God says, "Take your son, your
only son, and sacrifice him."
And in that
Jacob,
I mean sorry, Abraham
is faced with two things, two options.
Let go of God and keep your son or let
go of your son and stay hold keep your
hold on God.
>> What a uh what a choice.
>> Yeah. But even then, Abraham was saying,
"I will not let you go, God."
Both Abraham and Jacob fought
good fights in that way. And maybe what
it means to fight the good fight of
faith
is
I mean maybe the good fight is
you keep getting knocked down
>> but you refuse to stay down.
>> Amen.
It makes me think of that that story in
the New Testament where Jesus is um
walking with his disciples and a woman
comes up and starts um you know calling
out to him asking him to to heal her
daughter and he just turns around he's
like oh well you're not supposed to give
the food to the dogs you know don't take
the children's food throw it to the dogs
and to me that's almost like God saying
to Jacob let go and leave me alone it
And both Jacob and the woman didn't give
up. They were like, "Yeah, no. Sorry."
>> Yeah.
>> And it makes me wonder, what were they
basing their disobedience to that
command? You know what I mean? Like on
what were they basing that? Were they
basing that on on u things they heard
about God before, experiences with God
they had before?
>> Or were they basing it just on the fact
that okay, he can't really mean it or I
don't know. I'm just putting this
question out there. What were they
basing that faith on? Because God I mean
if it's it's a command of God. It wasn't
like the devil said, "Oh, stop. You're
not good enough." Right?
>> You know what I mean? That's that's
different,
>> right?
>> Wow.
>> Yeah.
>> That's an excellent question.
>> Good question, Manda.
>> And
>> I think that you you really have to have
a very real revelation of the goodness
of God and the mercy of God, the love of
God, the character that PhD first lady's
talking about. You got to have a PhD in
the character of God. You really got to
be holding on to that because if he told
me that, then the first thing I think I
would start thinking is,
>> man, I'm already messed up. He probably
trying to get rid of me, you know,
looking at me in that moment. I've got
to have it's got to be him.
>> Yeah.
>> I was reading uh lessons on faith from
uh at Jones and from the 1888 message
and and he said that Abraham had to
believe the word of God against the word
of God
>> in that moment. So whatever it was, it
had to be about God, about nothing else
but just God.
>> Yeah. When you like you said, Terry,
when you get a PhD in God, then you and
his character, then like you said, you
know that, okay, let me go doesn't mean
you're trying to get rid of me because
that goes against his character.
>> Yeah. And I and I like how you put it.
Uh the goodness of God.
>> The goodness of God. And I think that
goodness of God is the basis,
right?
Uh
why was a break of day in that story?
That's a good question. There's good
questions coming in.
>> Yeah, I have a question I want to cover
that somebody has. Yeah, you guys are
our audience is definitely a part of our
conversation, which you're supposed to
be.
>> So, so
that
they had to base it. Melinda, I think on
their conviction that God was good,
>> right?
That God was good. Um, they had to base
it on that faith
that this is who God is.
This is his character.
And
I'm not letting go of that picture.
So even Jesus on the cross,
my God, my God, why hast thou forsaken
me?
>> At that moment, he could have let go
because in his mind, he's saying exactly
what Jacob what Jacob is hearing. Let me
go. Let me go. And Jesus,
the father's trying to get away from me.
>> He left me.
Why have you forsaken me?
But in all of that, he never mentally
let go.
>> And could that be the demonstration of
fighting the good fight? Job,
Jacob,
Abraham,
Jesus.
So now
you know a easy fight is when you think,
"Oh yeah, everything is good. All is
well. God is with me."
It appears in that the good fight from
the examples that we've used at least
the good fight is when it looks like God
is not with you.
>> It feels like God isn't there.
>> Now,
now how do you fight
when your hands are tied behind your
back?
>> How do you fight when you're
blindfolded? How do you fight when you
can't feel the presence of God? How do
you fight when uh
uh
when it seems that everything
is against you? How do you fight in
those moments?
>> Right? The good fight is not so much
what happens when things are good. The
good fight is what happens when things
are bad.
Ironically,
>> right?
>> Yeah. Because that's where faith comes
in. It doesn't take faith.
>> It doesn't We don't have to utilize
faith when things are good.
>> We don't have to practice faith. You see
it. It's good. We're happy. Great.
>> We practice faith when it's bad, when
it's dark,
>> when it's black, when we don't have
anything
>> um that we're wanting. Somebody had
asked a question, what if the battle is
against fear? Like that's like their uh
they can't get over fear. Well, I just
want to say we had something that we
were going to start doing here and I had
mentioned it, but we never actually it
never started where we were going to um
because there's 365 verses and probably
more, but 365 verses where God says
don't fear. Mhm.
>> So, we were going to take one verse
>> a day or a week and like really just
really a day, not a week, but and look
at those verses and just talk about them
like kind of at the beginning when I'm
doing my t-shirt thing or something like
that. But we never really started doing
that. So, I I'm just saying that um I
think it's Heidi asked that question. Um
>> you know, there's so many verses in the
Bible that we can when I'm telling my
clients to do affirmations
>> when I'm I've even had a client do that
too when with the fear and the anxiety
was so high that you know and she was a
Christian so she was willing to do that
but um is to take one verse a day
>> and to claim that and to and to repeat
that to where you're not feeling it
you're feeling the feeling you feel is
fear but uh the words that you are
saying um are victory or comfort and
strength in God and you don't have to
worry you can just lay all of this with
him
>> um and so you don't have to be afraid
because he's not giving you that spirit
spirit. So if you're leaning upon him
and he's already not giving you that
spirit of fear, then he's going to give
you the strength to overcome fear
>> each moment that fear tries to
>> knock on your door.
>> Yeah.
>> So you can get definitely get victory
over fear. He that's almost like his
favorite thing to fight for you, help
you fight
>> 365 times in the Bible.
>> He doesn't talk about anything else. I
don't think that much. I don't think
I think he enjoys he he wants to give
you victory, Heidi, over fear. He wants
to give us all victory over fear.
>> He wants us to give us victory over
everything.
>> But I think it's so easy for him to help
us with fear that he's just like, "Let
me just remind them all these times that
I can help them."
>> And then, you know, you think about it,
a good fighter
isn't isn't afraid of fighting. I ask
you that because you guys all know he's
obviously been in many physical I don't
want to say a lot of physical fights.
I've never been in a physical fight and
I've asked you like aren't you scared to
but but you were never like in the
moment you're not scared
>> right
>> it's a fight.
>> Yeah. And I mean it's adrenaline.
>> Yes. I know.
>> So when adrenaline kicks in it's kind of
like that fear goes away right you're
not afraid anymore. You know the it's
it's fight or flight. And in flight is
the is the fear response. Fight is the
that mode that kicks in where you're
like
>> if I need to lift a car to save my baby
if I need, you know what I'm saying?
That kind of thing. So now the question
is how do we get that spiritual
adrenaline?
>> Spiritual adrenaline guys. We're not
promoting physical physical stuff.
>> Yeah. Spiritual
>> adrenaline.
>> How do we get that spiritual adrenaline
where
>> in that moment you're you're
uh um Samson
>> standing in the midst of, you know, a
whole army. You're David
uh going up against Goliath. You're
right. Fill in the blank in the Bible.
You are in that moment of spiritual
adrenaline and man that's that feels
like a whole study in itself. How do you
tap in the spiritual adrenaline?
David and Samson spent time. I know
Samson would had gotten to his situation
and he was blind and he had you know the
hair was cut and he was weak and da da
da but in that time
he was so humbled because he was always
like had the strength and it was always
winning and then he let Delilah come in
and do all her stuff
>> and I believe in that time he
reconnected with God. Yeah.
>> And he spent time with God. So when it
was time to like even though he was
blind and was in that situation, he
could push on those pillars and had the
strength to bring all that down. And the
same thing with David when it t came to
the fight. He had spent time with God.
So he was strong when the fight came.
>> So we need to be strong when the fight
comes. But we get that by spending time
with God.
>> Can intimate Okay. Intimate time with
God. Go ahead, Melinda. Go ahead.
>> Right. intimate time with God. Can I
propose that everybody who um was strong
in their fights with with uh their enemy
was, you know, filled with the spirit of
God like Samson, the spirit of God
overcame and he snapped the ropes and
David, I mean, obviously
>> he was, you know, told to do that by the
spirit of God. So, I think
>> I don't know if this is I don't know if
we can take it this way, but could the
spirit of God be our adrenaline?
>> Right.
>> I don't know. Exactly. Mhm.
>> It it spiritual adrenaline
>> is
>> the spirit of God.
>> Um
>> right because perfect love drives out
fear
>> and love is a fruit of the spirit.
>> Because I know for example like I don't
know I'm just going to give an example
for my personal life. Like I have
younger siblings, right? And when I just
take them places and like the parents
aren't around and I'm just like I'm just
scanning for like danger or like and I'm
telling you if if someone if someone
comes along and touches them wrong
>> they're they're cold on the floor like
and I'm not even scared. I'm just like
yeah you're cold on the floor. I'm
sorry. Don't touch my siblings. So I
know that that kind of not being afraid
of fighting because it's like yeah I
love these kids. Don't
>> don't touch them.
>> So I know what that's like where it's
like yeah I'm not scared. And I think
it's it really is perfect love drives
out fear because if I didn't love them,
I wouldn't want to defend them.
>> Yeah.
>> You know,
>> and and that is a that's a powerful
point because
that principle of perfect love cast out
fear really is
okay, right? Like if
um
Yeah.
Yeah. Um, my brother and I,
>> you knew you were
>> that was just it.
There was a time we were I don't know if
I shared this before here, but we were
we were in a club.
>> Yeah.
>> My brother was outside. I think I shared
it. He did share it here.
>> And you know, he was getting he got
>> I I just got told he's in a fight
outside.
And soon as I heard heard those words,
it was like, "Let's go." Like, "It's
done. Whoever touched my brother is
done." And I run out the club and I hit
the this there's stairs going down. I
kick open the door. I run out of and I'm
I see this crowd and I just jump in. I'm
thinking my brother's fighting like one
or two people and in the air I'm like,
"Oh,
there's like 12 people on my brother, my
little brother." And for a minute the
number just kind of like here's a whole
crowd here.
Didn't
ma like they could have had who knows
what they could have had, you know? They
could have had knives, they could have
had all kinds of it didn't matter at
that point.
There was no
fear of anything. So when
when you know someone is in danger that
you love, right?
>> When when someone's honor is in danger
that you love.
>> And so now we can't protect God, right?
So our fight is not I got to protect
God. He needs my protection. But that
honor
>> for God,
>> right? When God's honor is at stake,
when God's name is at stake,
>> man, you Christians, y'all don't know
how to live up to.
>> You get offended at the at the slightest
thing. You get offended at the easiest
thing. You lose your control.
>> That is not really an attack on you.
It's an attack on the God of the
universe. He doesn't have power to keep
you. He doesn't have power to hold you.
>> Doesn't have power to lift you up.
>> Yeah. And so that jealousy
right? So Song of Solomon chapter 8
>> verse six love uh is compared to coals
of fire that cannot be quenched. And
then the term love and jealousy are used
interchangeably.
>> So So now it's you know I was jealous
for my brother right I'm jealous for my
family.
Are we jealous for God?
>> And I think the jealousy of the jealousy
for God
is what
gets the fire
burning,
>> right?
>> Amen.
>> When you're jealous for
when you're jealous, you know, over your
spouse, over your boyfriend, over your
girlfriend, you don't want anybody.
Nobody. You're jealous over your kids.
You're jealous over your, you know what
I'm saying? You're like, don't touch
them.
>> And that absolutely
>> spiritual adrenaline,
which is the fire of God, which is the
spirit of God. It
>> You can only have it if you are jealous
for God.
>> Yeah.
>> And only if you love God.
>> Yep. Amen.
>> You can't be jealous for God.
>> That's powerful.
>> That's That's some powerful stuff. right
there. And and you know I was I was
thinking on the last on the last I think
on the last comment in the chapter of
the book you said so it must be for us
and our battle against self only then
can we fight a good fight. I have to see
myself as uh what did Paul say? Uh we
are spectacles. I've got to see myself
as God's property.
>> I really have to see that. And I've got
to see that when someone is offending me
or someone is coming against me,
>> that is the honor of God. And
>> and in the fight, I've got to manifest
that goodness. I can't overcome evil
with good. I mean, I can't overcome good
with evil, you know. I've got to I've
got to represent
>> the armor of God in that battle.
I' I've got to see that I love God so
much that I don't want to just like what
Joseph said, how can I do this thing and
sin against God, you know, and sometimes
we'll take it personal like the battle
is just all about us. But really, no, we
belong to him. We were created for him,
by him, and for his pleasure, we were
created. And so, I got to see myself as
whatever happens to me and whatever
comes against me, the honor of God's at
stake in my response.
>> Yeah. Um Moses
is leading the children of Israel out of
Egypt into the promised land. And then
God is like, "They've rebelled against
me. I'm going to destroy them."
And Moses is jealous for God. He's like,
"God,
>> if that happens,
then
the heathen are going to say this about
you."
>> So, okay,
let's see if we can work this out. I
have an idea.
Why don't you blot me out?
Right. That way, you know, I'll take the
blame for Israel.
>> So, they get to live, but your name
won't get uh blasphemed by the heathen.
>> So, you could blot me out. Like, let's
let's do that. And when Moses says,
"Blot me out,"
>> he's not just talking about death,
>> right?
>> He He's talking about blot me out of the
book of life. If you're blotted out of
the book of life, there is no eternal
life after. So Moses is willing
>> to actually not just die,
>> but willing to be blotted out forever.
>> Wow.
>> So that God's name not be blasphemed.
>> That is jealousy.
And I'm thinking like
>> you have to be want to protect God but
in that same breath
then you also
care about and love other humans
>> because you if you because you
>> because God loves and wants to protect
others as well. meaning like, you know,
we always like we're all in this
together.
>> No one is truly your enemy. Like you,
you know what I mean? We're to show
love. Even if somebody hurts us or maybe
even say something that we don't like,
>> um, our response should still be love
because God loves them.
>> Yeah.
>> That's that's a that's a struggle for us
as humans.
>> I Well, I'll speak for myself.
>> It is. First lady, you you you're you're
>> you're you're taking it you're taking it
to another level right there.
>> Well, I mean
that
>> it has to go to that level because we're
>> we're we're we're all striving. Look at
us. And I'm going to keep this in the
Christian realm. We It's easier for us
to show love to those, oh, those
non-believers. Let me show them Jesus
and let me teach them this. But once we
get with the family because y'all know
with the family we kind of we can act up
sometimes.
>> Absolutely.
>> We act up with the family. So, but like
here it is. We're all striving for the
same place. We all want to go to heaven.
All the Christians do.
>> Absolutely.
>> That we just do. That's what we want to
see. Jesus. We want to go to heaven. You
know, we want to come up and that first
resurrection if we, you know, are not,
you know, happen to, you know, pass away
or whatever. And we're all going to live
together. But
if we're not
practicing and having love for others,
>> even when they're wrong, even when they
hurt us,
heaven is not going to be a joy because
there's not going to be these little
fractions in heaven where like, "Oh
yeah, me and my friends are over here
and you and your friends are over there
there. The ones I really like, we're
hanging." We're all going to be together
and we're God is trying to train us to
teach us how to truly love because he
part of that PhD one of those classes.
It's the hardest class to pass and we're
kind of always in the class until Jesus
comes. But he's trying to train us how
to love others, those who do us wrong.
Because man, we did him wrong
>> and he loved us.
>> It's hard. Yeah,
>> it's definitely hard, but that's what he
wants.
>> That's what we have to have. That's
real.
>> Yeah. I think for it for it to get that
deep that the teaching we had and the
exercise pastor gave us for 40 days is
just beholding the lamb on the cross.
I've got to keep behold and let him cut
deeper and deeper and deeper until I
reach that place. He can do it if I
allow him to, but I've got to keep
looking. 40 days.
>> I've gotta see
>> the rest of your life is what it is. But
all of our lives. But go ahead. Sorry
for cutting you off. Go ahead.
>> No, no, you're No, we're fine. We're
fine. And and and I'm just saying
the deeper I look or you know by
beholding we're we're changed. We cannot
stop beholding. We cannot stop looking.
We cannot stop allowing him to cut
deeper and deeper because whatever it is
inside of me that makes me think, okay,
I've got the adrenaline now, the
spiritual adrenaline to defend the honor
of God, uh when it's my personal
testimony or when it's my children or my
family or somebody, but I need to allow
him to cut it so deep that even those
who may consider themselves my enemy,
God, how do I find this love? Because
that's the way you love me because I was
certainly your enemy. And so
>> the true test of the love of God in my
life is when I really it breaks my heart
to hurt someone and I and and it it when
we sit and think about it today just
being real. We find it too easy to hurt
our brothers and sisters. We find it too
easy
>> to talk behind our backs to open our
mouths and say things we ought not say
to have attitudes pick up them phones
and get to texting. And we we we really
need to cut deep saints. We really we
really
>> Yeah.
>> And and I thank you, first lady, for
allowing the Lord to allow you to take
us to that next step because that's
that's what we need to look at. And
pastor's been saying it all along, you
know, how do we how do we demonstrate
the true love of God for one another?
>> Yeah.
>> Saying at the same time, but
>> I don't know. It came out of my mouth.
But it's it's a struggle. I mean the the
the struggle is real as they say. That's
that that's a hard that's definitely the
hardest class to pass in God's character
in the getting the PhD because
>> because we get offended and we get
wounded and it's just and you know and
it's and people are wrong. They're like
legitimately wrong and you feel like I
have the right not to like you.
>> That's what you feel like.
Like I don't really like you now. And
and I say all and let me just say this
with there's still boundaries, okay?
Because we're in this sinful world. But
what's but we still need to love people
even if we have to love them from afar
because you know guys I'm I've been
preaching boundaries, okay? I'm the
whole therapist and we teach boundaries
all the time. But even if you have to
love them from afar because they're
extremely toxic, still in your heart you
have to love them. I mean you don't
allow yourself to be in a dangerous
emotionally abusive or dangerous
situation. Um, but
we're not to carry hate in our hearts
for even those who hurt us.
>> Amen.
I was going to mention and then this I
think this will be the last thing that I
that I share on this is um
you know uh
speaking about you know loving your
enemies right
>> um I think I I just may preach a sermon
about this but um God is
God wants to destroy his enemies.
He wants to destroy his enemies
>> and um
he
he does that in a different way and
there are two ways for him to do it.
>> Uh if the first way fails
then the second way is the way that he
doesn't want to do it.
>> So he he kills the old man.
That's how he slays his enemies.
>> Yes.
>> So,
>> you were slain. I was slain.
>> You know, Melinda, you were slain. He
killed He killed his enemies
>> and he killed them with love.
>> Wow.
>> Right. He killed them with with love.
Now, those who who who you cannot
destroy
>> by love
>> will then be destroyed
>> by the actual fire. Right?
>> So it's
>> two two paths for us or two ways we can
go. We can either be destroyed by the
fire of God. Now
>> and so when the Bible talks about, you
know, do not overcome uh evil with evil,
but evil with
>> goodness.
And it goes on to say um you know to to
pour hot coals
>> right
>> upon the heads of those that are our
enemies. I like to think of I like to
think of those hot coals as nine
different types of hot coals.
>> Love, joy, peace, longsuffering,
gentleness, goodness, faith, meekness,
temperance. So, I'm going to take a
stone of love. I'm going just throw it
at you,
>> right?
And the stone of joy.
>> And that's how we
>> God wants us to defeat our enemies.
>> Yeah.
>> He wants us to eliminate our enemies.
>> With the fruits of the spirit,
>> right? And how we eliminate them is with
the fruit of the spirit.
>> Right. There's a there's a there was um
when I was in my church back in uh
Templeton um
>> California
>> in yeah California Templeton uh
Templeton area
>> and there were two guys that I met um
and
they were both I met him at different
times
>> and they were both in gangs
>> and
We were at a I don't know if it was an
army bible camp
>> or where we were.
>> It was army
>> where they met each other for the first
time
>> and one of them was like, "Hey, me and
my friend were planning to jump you one
time.
I mean, it's just so crazy. God
literally slayed them."
>> I'm thinking of the same two people.
>> Yeah. Yeah. Uh
>> they were in the same area.
>> They were in Yeah, Templeton.
>> No, no, I know. Okay. No, I'm not
thinking of the same two people. I'm
thinking of one the same.
>> Yeah,
>> the other one lives somewhere else.
Anyway, go ahead. Sorry.
>> Yeah.
>> Okay.
>> So, the point is
>> they were literally getting ready to
kill each other
>> and now they were now they were
roommates, I think, at half
>> was Oh, I forgot about they did do that.
I forgot about that.
>> Roommates at AFCO.
>> Wow. Talk about God's way.
>> But they had become friends through Army
Bible Camp. And then they ended up being
roommates at AFCO because Yeah.
>> And I think it was there at AFCO that
they realized, wait a minute.
>> Yeah, you're right.
>> You the guys trying to kill.
>> How do you That's what I mean when I
when I say God wants us to defeat our
enemies.
>> Yeah.
>> Right. So in the future when you hear a
sermon coming up how to how to how to
destroy your enemy
>> and people gonna be like why in the
world is pastor preaching a sermon
called how to destroy your enemy
>> just y'all don't be surp everybody else
will be surprised and be but y'all don't
be surprised because you know exactly
where I'm going. I've given you a sneak
peek.
>> Amen.
>> Praise God.
>> And that's a good that's a good fighting
style.
>> A good fighting style is where you
defeat your enemies. You eliminate your
enemies. And that ought to be our goal.
I'mma I'mma eliminate my enemies one by
one.
>> Praise God.
>> Amen. Amen.
>> Yeah.
>> Yes. Do we have any closing thoughts? It
looks like
>> That was my closing thought.
>> That was your closing thought, but it's
from our guest. And looks like next week
we will be survival of meas. The
survival of
>> next week we're actually going to be uh
faith.
>> Oh, faith fighters.
>> We haven't even touched.
>> Yeah,
>> faith fighters. Okay. Sorry, I was going
too fast. Faith fighters.
>> I love that.
>> We got faith, then meekness, and
temperance. So, we got three more.
>> Okay. For
>> It's amazing how long we've been on this
chapter, you guys.
>> Chapter four has taken a minute, but
it's been a long nice minute. Yes.
>> Um, faith fighters. That reminds me of
of
faithful. Yes.
>> I was thinking about that earlier in
Sabbath school, but yes. Do you guys
have any closing remarks that you want
to share about goodness?
>> All right. you said all your remarks
within the study, but we do thank you
for uh doing Sabbath school with us
today and to continue to talk about the
Christian art of war. For those who are
viewing audience, please, if this is
your um if you haven't yet um signed
into mighty networks, please do so. And
I'll uh let you know how to do that
again um at the beginning of the divine
worship service. And they might put it
in the chat now as well. But you can
download each chapter. We have all four
chapters. That's what we've covered uh
so far in the middle of chapter 4. But
um all the other all the chapters are
there on Mighty Network. So you can uh
get it there uh so that you can be
studying along with us. We want you to
go on this journey with us. We love your
comments, your questions as we are going
through the Christian Art of War. It's
been such a blessing to have our panel.
It's our panel always is a little
different each week, but it's a blessing
who what God who God puts together that
week. It's always just perfect and a
blessing for uh what you're having to
share um what God has given you and for
you to share with all of us. So, we are
going to close off with in prayer. Um
but we do want to invite you to all stay
with us, continue to worship with us as
we go into the divine worship service.
Do you want to plug your sermon real
quick again?
>> Yes. So, the sermon you guys is entitled
The Veil, but I'm only giving you half
the title right now. I got to save the
other half because if I give away the
other half of the title, you will know
where I'm going. Well, you might know
where I'm going. And even then,
it's not what you think.
>> So,
>> please make sure you uh you invite uh
people to to the to the sermon. Um, it's
it's pretty profound.
Um,
and uh by God's grace, it'll be
life-changing.
>> That's right. Also, we're about to pray
and want to bring our guest back on as
we pray. But I also want to remind you
that if you have not subscribed, please
subscribe uh to our channel and like
this because we want to push it out
there to get as many people to see it as
possible. So that's that's your job
during our break is to subscribe and
like uh this channel and we want to just
pray with our with our viewing audience
and thank our guest again. So let's
pray.
>> Let's pray. Heavenly Father, thank you
Lord for uh giving us this opportunity
to to go deep into the fruit of
goodness. Lord, I pray Lord that uh what
we've shared today will be a blessing
not only to others but even to
ourselves. And Lord, we thank you um
Lord just for speaking uh speaking
through us Lord and for uh bringing your
word to life Lord and may it may it
change uh and transform us into your
image is our prayer in Jesus name. Be
with us Lord as we go into the divine
service and we thank you for hearing and
answering because we ask it in Jesus
name. Amen.
>> Amen. Amen.
>> Amen.
>> Amen. Thank you for having us. Happy
Sabbath.
>> Happy Sabbath. Thank you.
Happy sun.
>> On the northeast coast of the beautiful
Indonesian island of Bali is a small
coastal fishing village that contains a
historical relic that is larger than
life. A rare piece of history hidden
just off of the shoreline just a few
meters below the ocean surface. It is
one of the most beautiful and magical
places to visit in all of Bali. A place
to remember the past, to be in awe of
the present, and to learn the lessons
essential for a hopeful future. A
shipwreck from the Second World War,
lying in a watery grave that reminds us
of the power of living for a purpose and
leaving a legacy that is larger than
life.
The USS Liberty was a United States
cargo ship built in New Jersey in 1918.
This ship has had a very difficult life,
but in every season and circumstance, it
has continued to serve a meaningful
purpose. This ship served in the first
and second world wars as a cargo ship
for the United States military, aiding
in the fight for freedom around the
world. When in route from Australia to
the Philippines in 1942, she was hit
square on by a Japanese submarine
torpedo. Though damaged beyond repair,
she was saved from immediate sinking,
towed by the surrounding boats and
beached right here on the rocky shores
of northeast Bali in the Indonesian town
of Tulben. Though she would never sail
again, this damaged and deserted ship
became the source of valuable materials
of which she was stripped over the
ensuing years. For the next 20 years,
the Liberty sat on this rocky black
shoreline, resting in the shadow of
Bali's highest volcanic mountain. Then
in 1963,
Mount Aung erupted, sending lava,
earthquakes, and tremors down its slopes
to the shoreline. These tremors cause
the Liberty to slip off the rocky beach
back into the ocean where she lies
hidden in a watery grave to this day.
In this watery grave, she continues to
serve as the infrastructure for all
kinds of life to flourish. Just under
400 ft long, the Liberty now acts as a
giant marine housing complex. Hundreds
of different marine species call her
home. hard and soft corals, sponges,
nudie branks, crustaceians, hydroids,
and tropical fishes of every shape,
size, color, and texture. This dead ship
is actually more alive than ever before.
Every piece of it is covered with
thriving life and the creative colors of
abundant beauty. This dead ship is the
reason why many divers and explorers
visit the town of Tulen, boosting the
local economy and providing a meaningful
living to the beautiful people of this
place.
The Liberty was made with meaning,
designed with purpose, and fashioned
with function. Her creation had a
specific intention. Her design was for a
meaningful objective. She was used to
bring relief and fight for liberty and
freedom. Though she's been attacked,
abused, neglected, and is now resting in
a watery grain, her life was full of
meaning. And the same is true for you
today. My friend, you need to know that
there's a purpose for your existence.
You too were made with meaning and
created in love. But this doesn't mean
that life will always be easy. Life on
Earth is hard, just like this rocky
shoreline. And like the Liberty, living
out your purpose can be challenging.
There are many forces seeking to prevent
us from living out our God-given
purpose. Torpedoes trying to sink our
resolve. Minds seeking to blow up our
dreams, eruptions of negative energy
trying to consume whatever is left of
us. The USS Liberty lived a difficult
life. It endured many attacks and
persevered through much affliction. Now,
I don't know the storm that you might be
facing today or the fierce battles that
you're fighting that no one else can
see.
But this is something that I do know
that no matter what you're facing, you
can make it through it. Not only can you
survive, but by the grace of God, you
can thrive in purpose even during the
most discouraging of attacks. So don't
give up and don't give in. Now to the
surface observer, it seems that the
Liberty's purpose ended when she was
damaged beyond repair and left deserted
on this rocky beach. But for me, I see
that even in death, her usefulness never
died. Her end on the beach was really
the beginning of a new phase of meaning
and usefulness. At first, she was a
transporting vessel. Then she became the
source of valuable materials. And now
the remnants of her discarded wreckage
is the gathering place and the home of
so much life and beauty. Her impact in
death is even greater than her impact in
life.
Just like the USS Liberty, I challenge
you to live your life in the same way.
that when our time on earth is finished
and our face is seen no more, that the
legacy we leave behind will continue to
make a difference and that the impact of
our short existence here on earth will
never die. This is what our maker
desires for us to live in liberty and
meaning in every changing season of
life. To survive and thrive in purpose
despite all the assaults and the
attacks. to make a positive everlasting
impact upon those who see and surround
us. And that whatever work, legacy, and
memory that we leave behind, it will
continue to be a source of beauty,
wisdom, power, and inspiration and a
tangible impact for generations to come.
You can make a lasting positive impact.
And it starts with the choices that you
make today. Big and small. The choices
you make today determine who you will be
tomorrow. So let us live like the USS
Liberty for a purpose that is greater
than ourselves and a reason that reaches
far beyond after we're gone. For a life
lived in such a way shall never be
forgotten and the impact shall never
die. And may we strive to live that kind
of life today.
What other lessons can we learn from the
history of the USS Liberty? Please share
in the comments below. And when you have
a minute, please check out the rest of
our episodes shot around the world. Each
is unique and special. A perfect dose of
captivation, exploration, and
inspiration for your day. See more
episodes and partner with us at the
website below. Your monthly pledge will
empower us to continue creating
life-changing content for all. If you'd
like to join me on an epic excursion in
Hawaii, or create some meaningful
artistic imagery, vibe to the musings of
meaningful conversations, or see more of
my incredible views of nature and life,
check out my other websites here. And of
course, please connect with us on
YouTube, Instagram, and Facebook. Thank
you for your precious time, attention,
and support. Aloha always. Mahalo and
Marinata.
Heat. Heat.
Heat.
Welcome back, Living Mana Church family.
I'm so happy that you decided to
continue to worship with us today. If
you're just joining us for the first
time today, please put in the chat where
you're viewing from and we like we'd
love to say a special welcome to you.
And if this is your very first time, put
a one in the chat. If you didn't do it
during our first uh program, our first
service, please do it now. We would love
to see where everybody is viewing from.
We're just so happy that you are here
and you you decided to worship with us
today. We know that it is the holiday
season and many people are traveling and
visiting with family. Um, and that the
fact that you decided to tune in to us
here at Living Mana Church, we are just
so thrilled and happy to have you here.
So again, phat where you're viewing
from. Um, and and if this is your very
first time worshiping with Living Manage
Church, just put a one so I can tell you
more about Living Manage Church and the
online uh services that we do here all
throughout the week. We just want you to
know a little bit more about who we are.
If you missed Sabbath School today, wow,
it was such a blessing to be able to
talk to our panel about the Christian
art of war because that's what we are
all in. We are all in a battle just
because we have an enemy. So, we're all
in a battle, but because of God's grace
and his mercy and his goodness, which we
talked about today, we all have the
tools and everything that we need to win
uh this fight. And so, I am just so uh
thrilled to be talking about the
goodness of God and what he can do for
each and every one of us. We have some
of you guys have put in the chat where
you're viewing from. We have uh
blessings uh blessings joy is is
watching from Barbados. Welcome here to
Living Mana Church. We also have Crystal
Cox from Spokane, Washington. Crystal,
always good to see you. Welcome,
welcome, welcome. We love you. Uh it's
so good to have you here. Um and we have
Jennifer from Norway. Welcome, Jennifer.
And you didn't put a one, so you've been
here before, but it is good to have you
here from Norway, Jennifer. Um, or I'm
sorry. Jennifer is from Tennessee. I am
so sorry. We have someone else that's
from Norway, but you didn't put a one
either. Norway. So, this is not your
first time, but welcome. So, good to
have you here. We have I think it's
Bernice from Virginia. Welcome. Always
good to have uh you here as well. And we
have Evelyn from Bermuda. That beautiful
island, perfectly manicured island from
Bermuda. That's what I the first time we
flew in, I was like, "Wow, it's so
beautifully manicured and all of the
colors. It's just so pretty." All right.
And then we have Simon from Tanzania.
Welcome. Good to see you here. Uh love
our international church and that we
have people viewing from all around the
world. We're worshiping with people from
all around the world, guys. I just I
love it. I hope you love it, too,
because it's it's just a blessing to see
where everybody is watching Living Mana
Church from. And so I just want to let
you guys know how you can stay connected
to Living Mana Church because this is
really important because as you heard me
just say where some different people
are. Uh we're all around the world and
we're all around America. Want to say uh
welcome to Renee from San Jose,
California, just right down the street
from where we used to live. And then we
have Robert from Washington State, the
beautiful state of Washington. Good to
have you here as well, Robert. But just
letting you guys know how you can stay
to connected to Living Mana Church.
There's two ways that you can do that.
Uh if you are here in North America, you
can sign up to get text alerts. This is
so that you will find out when we're
going live. You won't you might forget,
but we're going to remind you, hey, this
program is coming on. Our church is
starting in 20 minutes. mental health
Monday or true health Tuesday or our
prayer service um our midweek prayer
service our power line or power
Wednesday. We'll remind you of those
things and we at times send other
messages as well. So this is the way you
can stay connected if you're in North
America. So you can just text LMC to the
855 number that you see there on your
screen and you will get those text
alerts. Now, as you saw, we have so many
people from all around the world. So,
you will want to sign up for Mighty
Networks. And I can see it's already in
the chat. The link to be able to sign up
for Mighty Networks is there. This is
our virtual church home. This is where
we form community here at Living Mana
Church. There's small groups there. You
can get to know the leaders. You get to
know other members, viewing audience,
all there and get messages as well on
mighty networks. And you could be
anywhere in the world and get these
Mighty Networks notifications. So this
is why it is so important to sign up for
Mighty Networks as well. But even for
you North America people, you want to
sign up for Mighty Networks because like
I said, this is our virtual church home.
So you're going to be able to do more
there than just get the text alerts on
your phone. You will be able to again
find out about small groups that you may
want to join. You can get to know other
members, other viewing audience there on
Mighty Networks. And there's so many
things our afterlow which will be today
after the the service after this uh
pastor sermon is over uh everyone as
many as people who want want to go they
will go on to mighty networks and they
will be on the afterlow. Pastor Myers
will be there. You might be able to ask
him follow-up questions about his sermon
or Sabbath school but talk to others as
well and just to discuss what you've
learned uh during the Sabbath service
and what blessed you. and um our
afterglow is just a blessing. And so
Mighty Networks is something you're
definitely going to want to sign up for
if you have not done already. Just to
remind you guys that we do have
children's programming and that is
through LMOC kids. We have amazing
leadership that um is with our kids and
teaching them the deep things about
God's word in a fun way. So they're
having they sing, they uh have art, they
learn about art, they make art, they
make art things, all type of different
stuff that they do. Uh they're an LMLC
kids that is kid-friendly. And we have
again great leadership that has um that
leads helps leads out and helps them
there. And um LMLC kids starts at 11:30
central time. And if you want to get
your child signed up, you can just text
kids to the 855 number or send an email
to the leadership team and they will get
back with you on how you can sign your
child up for LMOC Kids.
If you um also would like to get in
contact with Pastor Myers, he has
virtual church hours. So if you send a
message to Patrice at living.live, live,
she will schedule that appointment for
you so that you'll be able to meet and
talk with Pastor Meyers. Also, just want
to remind you guys about our if you want
to change or become a member of LMOC
Church for Living Mana Church, you will
be able to do that and the email that
you see on the screen is patrice at
living.live. And there's three different
ways that you can become a member. If
you are already a member of the 7th Day
Adventist Church and you just want to
transfer your membership, you will use
that patrice living.live email to do
that. If you um are not a member of the
7th Day Adventist Church, but you are um
a Christian and don't feel like you need
to be rebaptized, but you want to become
a member and you um have and you've
studied the things um in God's word that
the Seventh Day Adventist Church
teaches, you can join by profession of
faith. And so, um, you will also email
Patrice at living.live.
And if you're studying and learning
about what, uh, the Seventh Day
Adventist Church believes from the Bible
and you would like to be baptized, you
can also send an email to patrice at
living.live
and Pastor Meyers will baptize you and
that's how you'll become a member of our
church and of the 7th Day Adventist
Worldwide Church um, as well. And we do
have a baptism that's coming up in early
2026 because we had to postpone the last
baptism that was scheduled for November
15th because of the government shutdown.
But hopefully there'll be no more
shutdowns and we will be able to do the
baptism at the beginning uh of 2026 and
we will let you guys know when that is
going to happen.
So also if we want to tell I want to
tell you about the power line. The power
line uh is an amazing uh thing that we
have on YouTube that the living man of
church does and it is just amazing
because it is evangelist. It's an
evangelistic tool trying to win uh
people to Christ through prayer by
praying for them. And so that is every
Wednesday at 8:00 pm central time. Um
and so and just like it says it's
powerline we pray. There are people you
put your prayer request in the chat and
we pray right then, right there. And so
you can invite people to that say, "Hey,
can you pray for me?" Or, "I'm going
through this." And you can offer them,
"Hey, do you need prayer?" And they say,
"Yes." And you say, "Hey, I'm going to
have my church pray." They can come and
they can just um even if they don't want
to put the prayer request in the chat
themselves, you can do it for them. And
they will be able to hear live how
people are praying for them right there.
And so it's a great way to just uh lead
lead people and to know who God is and
the power of prayer and just to see how
God is going to work a miracle in their
situation. So again, the power line is
every Wednesday at uh 8 uh p.m. Central
Standard Time on YouTube. So you're
definitely going to want to check that
out. Also, we have a New Year's uh power
line that's going to be happening. So at
the so for New Year's Eve, there's going
to be a special power line that starts
at 8:00 p.m. Wednesday and that is
December obviously 31st. Um and it's
going to be at the same time it always
is at 8:00 p.m. And so the power line is
going to be praying and being um I don't
actually know how long they're going to
be on there. I don't know if they're
going to be on there until the new year.
I need to get information about that and
I'll announce it next week. But I know
that they're starting at uh 8:00 PM and
there's going to be a special program
and you see uh Terry and his wife Amra
who are our prayer leaders. They're
leaders of the prayer team. They are
going to be hosting. So you're not going
to want to miss that. And you know
sometimes the holidays can be, you know,
they can be lonely if you're not with
the ones you love or if the ones you
loved have passed, you know, passed
away. And so spending time together
especially for Christmas and on New
Year's Eve. And there's no better way
than to do it than in prayer. So we're
definitely inviting uh everyone to come
and to um experience prayer at the power
line on New Year's Eve.
Want you guys to uh I know many of you
who have been on you know about LMLC
Global, but this is just a reminder that
you know this is why we're here. This is
why we're online so we can reach as many
people as possible. And yes, we could
have stayed in a brick-and-mortar
church, but that would have limited and
limited our reach. So, you know that
Living Man Church is here for that
reason. So, we want to go into the world
uh with the languages of the world,
meaning we want to be able to share as
to preach and to share in as many
languages as possible. Right now, we
have seven languages. And for those of
you who that have not seen or not
familiar, we just want to show you a
little bit of what that looks like and
how you can help us to continue to be
able to do it. So let's what that let's
see what that looks like right now.
Kindche.
You see how powerful that is where we're
able to go into the language like in
Hindu so many millions of people speak
Hindu in this world and to be able to uh
preach in their language and share in
their language is just amazing and we
want to be able to do that in so many
more languages or continue to do it in
the language ages that we have been
doing so far. So, the way that you're
able to support uh Living Mana Global is
that you can go to Adventistgiving.org.
This is the way you're able to give and
to support Living Mana Church in
general, but you can also by doing that
you're helping uh to support LivingManna
Global. And so, you can go um on to
Adventistgiving.org or and click on that
right hand corner and put in what church
you're wanting to support which is
Living Mana uh Church with the
Northeastern Conference and there a
virtual tithe envelope will fall down.
You'll be able to see that you can give
your tithe again which goes to support
the Northeastern Conference. Then
there's an area there for the local
church which helps us to do all the many
things that we do here at Living Mana
Church including uh Living Mana Global.
Um the all the equipment that that we uh
use here to be online and have uh a
professional presence if you will here
online. When you're giving to the local
church budget, it helps us to do that.
Um, we've grown as a church, so we have
uh a few employees. And so, when you're
giving to the local church budget,
you're helping to support all the things
that our local church here at Living
Mana uh Church does to be able to go
into all the world to be live and
broadcast to all of you all around the
world each and every week and to do that
all throughout the week. uh that we also
have a benevolence fund there on the
tithe envelope and that helps us to be
able to give to others uh when they are
um in need and requesting some
assistance from the church. Um and if
you don't want to if you don't want to
uh give through advent giving that but
that you prefer to mail in uh your tithe
and offering you you can do that with
the address that's on the screen there.
P Box 428 Owens Crossroads, Alabama
35763.
So that's the address that you can use
to be able uh to mail in again your
tithe and offering. And if you just put
on a note, a little note in the envelope
where you're wanting um your love gift
to go, how much is for tithe, how much
is for offering, and exactly where you
want it to go, uh we'll be able to do
that for you. So again, you know, this
is just a time to say thank you to all
of you for supporting Living Mana
Church. In 2026, in April 2026, it'll be
four years. It's sometimes a little hard
to believe that we have been here for
four years, almost four years, but God
has been so good to Living Mana Church.
And he has used all of you through your
prayers, through your financial gifts,
through you sharing the links and
talking about Living Mana Church and
what we do here. And we are just so very
thankful. We are thankful to God. And we
are thankful um on how you've responded
to God and how he uses you to help to
support uh this church. And we just pray
that during this holiday season again,
it's such a busy time and people are
doing so many things, but God is the
reason for this season. And so we want
everyone to just be encouraged and not
to forget that and all of the hustle and
the bustle. But it's also very important
to just spend time with family and to
slow down and just enjoy uh this time um
with God and with family and just to
continue to allow God to work in your
life and to use you. But it is a special
very special time. And again, we just
want to say thank you for all of your um
support of Living Mana Church. And we
just ask God that he will continue to
lead the church and bless the church and
show us what directions to go to, how to
be more effective and reaching the world
um in all the different ways that he's
going to show us and give us to be able
to do that. So, I just want to say a
prayer of thanksgiving at this time um
as we just just give praise and
thanksgiving to God. So, please bow your
heads with me as we pray.
Heavenly Father, Lord, I want to thank
you for this Sabbath, Lord. want to
thank you uh just for your faithfulness
and what you do for each and every one
of us. Lord, as my t-shirt says, like
faith doesn't make things easy all the
time, but it makes things possible
because we are believing in the one that
can do that can change and fix anything.
So, we never have to worry, we never
have to fear because we just need to
have faith in you. And Lord, we are just
coming today. We are all coming to just
thank you for all that you um again have
done for each and every one of us. Lord,
that doesn't mean we haven't gone
through trials. We know people are going
through so much um Lord just in in their
family life, Lord, with their finances,
um with their health. There's so many
categories, Lord, out there that we uh
go through things in life, but you are
there to help us in each and every
situation we go through. And so, we want
to praise you for that. We want to thank
you for that. And Lord, I just ask that
everyone, all those categories that I
mentioned, Lord, with family and health
and finances and all of the things that
we go through, Lord, I am asking that
every person who is viewing that is
going through one of those areas or
something that I didn't mention, Lord,
that you will actually just step into
their situation. Lord, I'm praying for
them even though I don't know the actual
request. I'm praying that you will work
in their life and you will bless them um
as you are there. Let them feel you and
know that you are there in their journey
with them. Lord, I want to lift up
Pastor Meyers and the sermon that you
have given to him. Lord, I am praying
that through the Holy Spirit, it will
just bless us, the viewers, and it will
touch our hearts in a powerful way,
Lord. And it will change us. It will
draw us closer to you. That is my
prayer. And I ask all these things in
Jesus name. Amen.
>> Jesus is coming. The season of Advent is
here. The season of joy. May joy rise
within you this Christmas season. Like
light breaking through the dawn. As you
gather, bake, wrap, and sing. May joy
find its way into every little moment.
Filling your traditions with a deeper
meaning this year. For true joy was born
in Bethlehem. Not the fleeting kind of
joy that the world offers, but the
everlasting joy of a savior who came for
you. The one who shatters sin and shame.
The one who calls you out of darkness
and invites you to dance in his
marvelous light.
From the star that gleamed over the
stable to the light that now shines in
our hearts. May you be filled
overflowing
and radiant. Be blessed with joy this
Advent.
Silent
Holy
night
is bright
mother and child
in soul.
And
sleep
in heaven.
Sleep
Oh, silent
night,
holy
night.
She
quart.
Heavenly
single
Christ
the Savior
is born.
Christ the Savior is
Here at Living Mana, we bear each
other's burdens.
When you need support or prayer, when
you're feeling discouraged
or alone or anxious,
you don't have to face life struggles
alone.
Let us come boldly unto the throne of
grace that we may obtain mercy and find
grace to help in our time of need.
The Lord is close to the brokenhearted
and saves those who are crushed in
spirit.
Greetings living mana family, friends,
visitors, saints of the most high God.
Everyone, welcome to another edition of
Living Manners Prayer and Praise Time. I
am brother Terry. This is my lovely
bride Amra. We just want to say we love
y'all. Thank God for y'all and uh we're
happy to be here serving and worshiping
right along with you today. Saw all the
shout outs go out in the chat. Everybody
from everywhere. I just wanted to greet
you right now and say uh thank God. Uh
you know um we were talking about the
goodness of God today. Hope you enjoyed
the uh um Sabbath school study. Want to
encourage you to pick up that book, The
Christian Art of War. Let the Lord speak
to you. Doesn't matter what we say here
and how many insights we share. There's
nothing like when you hear from the Lord
for yourself and he speaks uh words of
life directly into your situation.
>> Amen.
>> And so uh so wonderful. Brother Clint,
shout out to you, my brother. Love you
so much. Saw you in the chat there just
now. Other folk definitely. Sister
>> blessing.
>> Yes. Yes.
>> Christy
>> Christy from South Carolina. Love you.
>> Rusty Chase.
>> My favorite memories from this time of
year are right back there in South
Carolina. Well, God's given me some new
memories right here. And so, uh, what a
beautiful thing. I want to share
something in just a moment, but for now,
um, want to hand it over to my lovely
bride and let her do some praise
reports, but I see you, Regina, coming
up in the chat and others coming up.
Happy holidays to y'all and and praise
the Lord. Happy Sabbath most of all for
those of you who who know the goodness
of God and what he's provided for us in
this special time. So, love y'all. Love
y'all. Love y'all. I want to send a
special shout out right now to to the uh
uh Living Mana uh prayer warriors and
warheads. You know, uh I don't know if
we do that enough. Just stop and say
thank y'all. Listen, these prayer
warriors are just amazing
>> something something else. God has really
raised up a mighty prayer team. They're
praying and listen um standing in the
gap and fasting and just seeking the
Lord. And let me tell you something. We
know the difference. We feel the
difference. We experienced the
difference. I'll come back in a minute
and tell you. I don't want to get in
trouble and get ahead of myself, but
there's something I need to say to you,
somebody watching right now.
>> Well, amen. You know what? I just want
to say hello to Denise.
>> Hello.
>> Yes. How could I not have shouted out
sister Denise
>> Elco Jennifer Logan Imagigene
>> John Heasley
Ross
>> and Gina
>> yes well you know what thank you for the
compliments on our red you know tis the
season so
>> yes I knew yeah amen
>> amen all right
>> yes
>> all right before I go into the praise
reports
>> brother Kashie
Much love, my brother.
>> Yes.
>> Hallelujah.
>> All right. If you have a prayer request
or a praise report or you would like to
join us on the prayer team or a special
ops group under the prayer team
umbrella, we always are looking for
people to join our ministry. Please send
a email to praymanana.urch.
If you are requesting a special ops team
for yourself or a loved one, please send
an email to spec ops. That's spcops
at livingmana.urch.
>> Amen. Just a reminder, if you need a
midweek pickup, please join us on Power
Wednesdays. That's every Wednesday at
4:30 p.m. 6:30 Central time, 7:30
Eastern Standard Time. It is such a huge
blessing. We either have a personal
testimonial from someone or we have a
devotional and then we have some really
powerful prayer time and it's just a
time of fellowship and spending some
time in the community. Following that,
we have the power line that starts at
6:00 p.m. Pacific Standard Time, 8:00
p.m. Central, 900 p.m. Eastern.
If you would like to join the women's
ministry on mighty networks, please send
an email to women wena.urch.
And finally, if you would like to join
the men's ministry, please send an email
to menlivingmana.urch.
>> Amen. Amen.
>> All right. Starting us off strong on
praise reports is our lovely Imagigene
Wright.
Grand rising lovely family Amra. I have
an answered prayer I'd like to share
that the prayer team prayed for. Last
week I asked prayer because I had to go
back to a follow-up exam which the
doctor was concerned about.
>> On Wednesday, I went to the appointment
and they did about five different tests.
The doctor said that the test showed a
negative outcome and it wasn't the
concern that he thought so to come back
in six months. I'm thanking the Lord for
his mercy which is new every morning and
the prayer team for their dedicated
hearts for every single prayer that
comes before them. May the Lord bless
them.
>> Amen. Amen.
>> Amen. Amen. From Olivia Torres or Olive
as we like to call her.
Praise God for his new mercy every
morning. We are urged to pray earnestly
and fervently because we need a supply
of mana daily. This must be one of my
unspoken prayer requests before, but
thank you for your continued prayer on
my behalf. I prayed that the bank would
approve my request for a loan extension.
My mortgage maturity date is at the end
of the year. After months of back and
forth phone calls, follow-ups, and
electronic paper trails, our prayer is
granted. Hallelujah. Truly, the God we
serve is faithful, gracious, and
merciful. It put my mind at ease that I
will not default on my payment, and the
fear of foreclosure haunted me. He keeps
his promise when we ask with purpose and
intentionality.
Lastly, I need to thank you all for
keeping me in your prayers. And I praise
God for every remembrance of you. And
please continue to pray for my children,
most importantly their walk with God.
Not the perfect scenario. They are so
indifferent and rebellious in their
hearts. I will spare you all the details
set it set in their own ways. Overall, I
am pretty sure anyone here on this
prayer chat can very well relate to our
deepest desire to see our children in
the faith. Have a blessed Sabbath,
dearly beloved.
>> Amen.
>> Amen. From Spamco Pac
from the course I took with Professor
Blue, I was inspired to do something in
my area in the country of Serbia. In a
village in my area, there was a school
that was in need of repairs. But when I
spoke to the mun municipality mayor,
they didn't want to do anything about
it.
>> So, I took a loan of 2,200 to buy paint
for the school in that village.
>> 150 great controversies and 20 Bibles.
My daughter thought that I had lost my
mind. Please pray for her.
I didn't have that much money left over
for only Bibles. So, I had to change my
plans. There was only enough for 20
Bibles, so I had to split it between a
Bible together with the Great
Controversy and only the Great
Controversy. But in every book, I wrote
down several Bible promises.
>> In the picture, you can see one of the
workers at the municipality reading the
Bible verses I'd written down in one of
the Bibles. What surprised me was that a
woman nearby wrote down these Bible
promises when she heard them. So, I need
to memorize more. Another peculiar thing
that happened was that while we were
painting the school on a weekend, some
farmers came to clear all the forest
trees and bushes, blackberry bushes,
weeds, etc. near the school.
Even they were afraid of what the
Orthodox priests would say if they would
help to clean on the weekends. Praise
God. That is one for Christ.
Finally, Kimberly Boute,
God has poured out so many miracles on
my life in such a short amount of time.
I believe that my testimony is ready. He
has blessed me so much. First, I have
not worked in nine months. My rent went
up and most of my bills and my daddy's.
Yet, I still have my own place, food to
eat, and all bills paid and good health
and much more has happened. Now, how all
of this happened was the scariest and
hardest journey I've ever had. The
details are everything. I am ready to
share these, and we are looking forward
to hearing them. I still don't have a
job, but all my needs are provided, and
it's coming in his timing. Thank you for
all your prayers.
Well, Kim,
this particular praise report really hit
home for me.
>> Yes.
>> And I could resonate with this so much
because this week I learned the news
that myself and 29 of my co-workers were
laid off our jobs this week and my last
day was yesterday.
And so
um I put had posted on Facebook and
LinkedIn about my situation
and I decided I wanted to write a list
of praises and blessings during this
journey. So, I want to share these with
you just so you guys will be encouraged
that just in the last couple days, most
of this happening yesterday on my last
day on the job, um I just wanted to
share what God has already been doing,
which is just incredible. And I wrote it
down so I don't forget anything.
And keep me in prayer, please. And Terry
and I in prayer.
So, um, yesterday, eight people shared
my post on LinkedIn on their feed to
reach their networks.
My former VP of marketing, who was let
go two years ago, reached out to me and
said she had freelance work after the
holidays if I'd like it. She also said
she would share my info with her
business groups and that she recently
moved to California about an hour from
me, so now we may actually get together.
Another former co-orker who was let go a
few years ago reached out to me and said
she absolutely loves the new company she
is working for and that their creative
team is amazing and that when she comes
back in the new year after vacation, she
will share my website, resume, and
portfolio with her manager to see if
they might be able to make room for me
there. She said she would love to work
together again.
My former boss from another company
highly complimented me on my resume and
portfolio and said she'd share my info
and help me look. She was so incredibly
kind. Yesterday,
one of my company's main recruiters sent
me a private message and said she'd
review my res resume this weekend and
share connections with me in her
network.
The marketing director of my company
sent me a private me private email and
she also made it clear that she was not
making the decision to lay me off. This
came from the very very tippy top. She
sent me a private email CCing my brand
manager on the marketing team asking if
I was interested in doing freelance work
on a project by project basis and we can
discuss my hourly rate when I return
from the holidays. My local bestie
blessed me by taking me out to dinner
Thursday night and gave me some
thoughtful Christmas gifts and said she
shared my news with her church's prayer
team and one of them sent me some
resources already.
a Jewish virtual friend who I met in a
social group on Facebook but have never
actually spoken to or met in person
shipped me a gift worth $150
just to cheer me up. And finally, I was
gifted a free trip for five days across
country to spend some time with the
girls to bring me joy. I was told this
was a gift from the Holy Spirit and a
way to show his love towards me.
>> Wow.
>> So good.
>> So, you know, this week I had I mean,
honestly, just a heavy heart knowing I
was losing my job and I had to say
goodbye to people. But then on the flip
side, God is just showering me right and
left and showing me blessing and favor
and
>> his love like seeping through the the
new season I will be embarking on.
>> Yes. And so let me let me say this
>> saints. Y'all already know the year
we've had. It's been a tough year
>> with with all of the with all of the
with all of the the hospitalizations,
with the sepsis, and all of the
specialists. And so, we come through and
we give our testimony at Power Wednesday
the other night. We're really happy to
be coming out of that storm. And you
hear Brother Terry sitting here talking
about, "Hey, saints, we're spiritual
stormtroopers. We're either in the
middle of a storm or we're coming out of
one and heading into another one." And
so, it's one thing to sit here and say
that. You know, we can smile for the
camera.
>> These smiles are real because let me
tell you something. Right after all this
stuff happens, then Amar gets laid off.
Now, you can imagine what brother Jerry,
he might sit at this desk looking all
composed and polished and kicking up
under the surface because all that's
going on. But I want to say something
about the God we serve. He sends us or
he allows us to go through these things
sometimes, saints, so that he can
manifest his goodness in our lives. I'm
telling you, somebody going through it,
look for the blessing. Mhm.
>> So, we begin to talk and you know,
pastor, by the way, pastor has this
photo theology GPT app. And I'm telling
you right now, saints, you need to get
it. Everybody needs to get it. You need
to sign up. We'll talk more about it.
You'll hear more about it because I'm
sure we're going to be talking a lot
more about it. That thing is something
else.
>> And so, what we did, we went into the
devotional tab and we created u a
devotional for me and Amra, a 40-day
devotional. We begin to just go into the
word already. And Ammer was getting
ready to, you know, we're reerecting our
family worship altar in our home. We
were renewing renewing our covenant with
God and we're just, you know, getting
before God, reminding him of his
promises, his blessing. Not that he can
forget anything. And we just he just
brought us to that personal revival
place. And so we took all this stuff and
we loaded it into that devotional. And
that devotional started spitting out
things that were just too perfect. And
it was so personalized even
>> so personal.
>> My name of my job loss like all the
things. It was really nice.
>> Look, I'm not just plugging this photo
theology app. You need to get that
thing. I'm telling you, and if you got
it, you need to use it. Encouraged me a
lot.
>> Listen, but the thing that came upon us
was Jerei Jeremiah 29:11, which
everybody loves. back away from that and
start at verse one and read the whole
thing. God was telling them to be
productive in the middle of their mess,
in the middle of their captivity. Get
ready, realign, get rooted, grounded,
and settled, anchored for the next
season that's coming. See, you may be in
that job and God says, "I'm going to
bless you with something better. I got
something better for you. So, this going
to look bad and feel kind of bad, but
it's you got to let go of that so I can
give you this." And that's what he's
doing. build the foundation
to prepare you for the blessing. He has
>> for the blessing that's coming.
>> He has to prepare.
>> Oh, somebody, somebody, somebody. You
feel like the bottom falling out of it.
You feeling like everything's falling
apart around you. Look, God is in
control of this thing. He has never lost
a battle, never lost a fight, never
never failed, and never will. Somebody
and I know it feels. Sister Tante was
talking, first lady was talking about
her friend, you know, who said, you
know, let's just praise the Lord. You
know, that reminds me of Sister Pauline.
>> You know,
>> I told Pauline, I lost my job. And you
know what? Paul,
>> first thing out of Pauline's mouth,
>> praise the Lord.
>> Praise the Lord. I was like,
>> what? You know, but but that's it.
That's it, saints. And and once we
practiced like pastor and first lady was
saying get the accustomed to it and
cooperating with God and seeing when
Israel was in captivity God came and
told him listen when 70 years are
accomplished I don't know sister
Kimberly Boute I remember when you and I
started sharing emails praying about
your situation when nine months are
accomplished or Kimberly when when six
weeks are accomp accomplished Christie
when when when three days I imagine I
don't know but God has an appointed time
for each of your seasons. And all we
want to say to you is in your season, be
productive. Praise, worship, get in the
word, study, fast, research, draw near
to God in your mess, and he going to
bring you out on the other side as pure
gold. Somebody, I know we're not, this
ain't preach time, this prayer time, but
you got to get excited about this thing
because of God. And listen,
>> I just s thought of something else. this
evening. My company just happened to
invite us to our company
>> holiday party or whatever it is. And I
and and some special things happening.
>> And so God is just setting all kind of
stuff up somebody. And I believe he put
us here. He put it on the pastor and
first lady's heart to have us sit here.
This is the first time you're going to
see me in Ammer. The last time you're
going to see us in the year 2025 because
next week our beloved brother Danny and
sister Jacqueline Clark are going to
come and do what they do. So, well, such
a blessing to us and such a blessing to
living mana. They are, believe me. But I
just wanted to take a little bit more
time just to say this. God is in
control. Somebody watching, somebody
tuning in, somebody's feeling like it's
all over. His goodness will manifest in
the m in the middle of your mess. Hold
on. Hold on.
>> And his timing is perfect. I just
recalled these layoffs that my company
have been doing started two years ago.
This layoff this week was the seventh.
So God has sustained me all through
these last two years up until this last
seventh one. Seven. Yes. Isn't that the
number of completion? Anyway,
>> people who were there before you,
executives who were there before you
lost their jobs before you.
>> Executives lost their jobs this week
alongside me. some shocking ones. So, I
actually felt like
>> I don't know why I felt kind of relief
that it wasn't just me. Anyway,
>> but the thing our God is saying is this,
my love. He's saying this,
>> your circumstances, your situation, your
destiny, your your his purpose for your
life has absolutely nothing to do with
what's going on with everybody else. A
thousand may fall at your side, 10,000
at your right hand, but it shall not
come nigh thee. Only with thine eyes
shalt thou behold and see the reward of
the wicked. And but God has a plan for
you. Somebody God has a plan for you.
Get in his word. Get that photo theology
app. Get that thing. Put your situation
in there. Get to the devotion. Type in
what your situation is. Type in there
and let Pastor Myers bless your heart
with over 20 some almost 30 years worth
of studying and being led and guided by
the Lord. It's in there. It's downloaded
in there. We're going to come talk more
about that. I'm going tell you, God got
something for you. living manner.
>> God's timing is perfect.
>> Yes. Yes. Yes. Yes.
>> And he orchestrates all good things.
>> Yeah. And start start practicing. If you
need to spend time with, like he said,
practice with somebody who's a master,
someone who's better, someone who's
good. Practice with Sister Pauline. Just
call her up. Tell her what your
situation is. Can tell you right now.
First thing out of her mind. Praise the
Lord.
>> Praise the Lord.
>> Yes.
>> We love Pauline.
>> Amen. Amen. And so saints, what we
always do, let's go to the throne of
grace together and and seek our God in
faith. And what we're going to do today,
I want to introduce a warette, uh, a
beautiful warrior. She's a a member of
the prayer team. She's always available,
always praying. You can see her in every
huddle, every prayer meeting. Every time
the prayer team has something going on,
fasting and praying, 24-hour fasting and
praying, she's there. She's been such a
sweetheart ever since she's been here. I
think she came on one time and led the
church in intercessory repair. But today
she's back with us. In fact, you saw her
early this morning when she showed up at
Sabbath school, but then they took her
down. But but look, she was ready for
that, too. I mean, Sister Karen Wright,
beautiful sister Karen Wright, we'll
thank God for you as you come forward to
take us to lead us to the throne of
grace this morning.
>> Happy Sabbath.
Happy Sabbath, everybody.
>> And yes, I was on this morning. I was on
this morning and I said, uh, it's a call
to duty. That's it. It's it's a call to
duty and I'm ready. Use me at your will,
Lord.
>> Amen.
>> All right. So,
all right. So, our um first prayer
request is from Sister Angela, and it
says, "Here in St. Louis, several people
seem to be killed getting killed daily
on the highway. This young man stopped
on the side of the uh of the highway to
help this young lady change her tire.
Someone came and hit them both. They
both died. They were both so young. Her
heart aches for their families. Not just
because it's the holidays, but because
they are not coming home. Say a prayer
for their families.
And then um let's see.
Got a lot here. Uh it says uh from
Lawrence. It says from France. I
received this prayer request, urgent
prayer request for Lar Roach de Gloom.
At the checkout of the mini market, I
heard a grandmother fighting to regain
custody of her two grandchildren, aged
two and four, following the tragic death
of their young parents, age around 24,
in a car accident. Their names were
Florian and Natasia. Their mother worked
at the point de laser shelter. Their
children are at risk in ending up in
foster uh of ending up in foster care
because the legal process is very
complicated. They were able to sleep at
their house last night.
I asked the cashier to tell her that
someone would pray for this situation.
May uh these orphans be able to stay
with their family. Amen. And thank you
for joining me in prayer. And then from
Martell Peters, it says, "As I
continually thank God for the commitment
for my benefit and all in you all
standing in the gap for me and providing
your your uh combined love for God in
doing his will for his children. The
restaurant that I have worked for 14
years will be closing on December 28th.
I am asking for continued provision
before an extension of faith at 71 years
of maturity to abide in his promises and
look up to behold his vis so that I may
see all my trials as a wisp and of
denial
of what he has in store for me. Thank
God for Jesus and he is under our
prayer.
And for Clint Ives, it says prayers for
a young girl at our church. She is
around 7 years old and her name is
Paris. She has asthma and double
pneumonia. She is not doing well. She
could really use some support. Thank you
all and God bless.
And then this is from um our sister,
sister Amra. As you've already heard
from her, she says, "Hi, prayer team.
I'm still uh processing this fresh news,
but I was but I was just laid off from
my full-time job and my last day is this
Friday. Please pray that the Lord will
provide all our needs financially, that
I will be able to get a MacBook Pro to
be able to do freelance projects, and
that the door will be open to a new
full-time remote position ASAP. I
appreciate your prayers and support.
This has been a super rough year for me,
and this was the grand finale, I guess.
My coworker was laid off as well and
several others are being let go today.
So, please pray for them and their
families too. Thank you.
Okay. And then I have here
it says from Ramona Brady, "Prayer for
my only daughter Mercedes
uh dismutes
passing her clinicals."
Okay. And then from Francis Grant 911,
please lift Imani up on prayer. She is
at the court for the hearing concerning
her 2-year-old daughter to be able to
get her back to her custody. Immani's
position was vastly improved where she
can take care of her daughter. She is
working and going to school and is
living with the aunt that was with her
when her daughter was born.
Unfortunately, her aunt is sick and
unable to to come to the hearing. Immani
is a young 20-year-old mother going
against an older woman who she has asked
to take care of her child when she went
to VA
to V Virginia trying to um find work.
She is back in New Jersey and the woman
and her daughter who has her child are
refusing to give back the child. And
that's why we are we are at court today
pleading for the Lord's touch and
intervention now. Thank you for your
prayers, Sister Francis Grant.
And uh it's from Sister Pauline. This is
Shaina Major's mom. I want to thank you
for your continuous prayers for Major
and my apologies for not giving an
update.
Uh he is his health has been stable. But
there are some kinks in to still work
out. I have been praying for these
things below. Major's prayer request.
Health. His body will absorb his
nutrients. Put on weight and grow
healthy. No inflammation or silent
inflammation.
Complete healing. Discernment for
parents on how to continue feeding him
and caring for him properly. Thank God.
Oh, I'm sorry. that God will supply our
needs and for school to have a
successful school year to pass all his
state exams. Also pray that he as well
as his family will continue to trust and
have faith in God. Thank you again for
your prayers. We appreciate it more and
more.
Appreciate it more than you know.
And this is from our sister Pat. Major
is her 10-year-old. Oh, saying Major is
our 10-year-old son who has Crohn's
disease.
Okay. Then this is from sister Lawrence.
Prayer request. Our car has just broke
down and my daughter desperately needs
it tomorrow morning for work. She can't
do without it. Thank you for your
prayers that the garage can take it in
urgently tomorrow at 8:00 a.m. and above
all that the problem is not irreparable.
Exactly. Praise God. And uh from Sister
Pauline, please pray for Miss Wyn. Her
family is grieving the loss of a cousin
to cancer.
For uh Sister Annette, please uh keep my
son Daniel in prayer. Yes, court today.
Um, may God's will be done.
Okay.
And then this is from myself. It says,
"James is a friend of my family. He fell
down 14 steps, broke three ribs, has
sepsis now, and is in ICU, heavily
sedated, but stable." Please pray for
God's hands of grace and mercy to cover
and deliver him through this storm in
Jesus precious name.
And I think
oh it says um
from sister Jackie.
It says please pray for me for priest
please pray with me from Nikesha who is
experiencing discouragement and de
demonic attacks. She occasionally
attends our Wednesday services and is a
young mother that's going through a lot
right now. from Sister Sharon
prayer team. Please join me in prayer
for for Barbara Holiday. She had to stop
caring for her uh for my co-worker's
elderly mom because her cancer re
reoccurred. My coworker's friend Wendy
Boyd.
The doctors found nodules on her
thyroid. And um my other coworker Vandra
Litz, her daughter is in the hospital.
She's not doing well and is not
responding to the medicine. Thank you
prayer team for your love, support, and
prayers.
Okay.
So, I'm going to go to the throne room.
Heavenly Father, we just give you all
praise, glory, and honor for being our
God, being our king, and uh being so
loyal and so faithful to us. We ask for
your will to be done for uh that family
where the two young people were killed
on the side of the road. Lord, we just
thank you that hearts and minds will be
troubled. Hearts we the hearts and minds
that will be troubled because it is the
Christmas season that you will uh love
and care for those tender hearts. Give
them your tender mercies. Share your
tender mercies. And father God, we thank
you that you'll nourish those souls and
allow their uh minds to be at peace, the
perfect peace that comes from you. And
Father, for the grandmother is fighting
fighting to gain custody of those
children. I thank you, Father, that she
finds favor in your sight. What she's
doing is she's trying to get those
grandchildren in her custody. And I
thank you that you intervene and allow
that to happen on her behalf. And father
for uh brother Artel uh the restaurant
was closing after 14 years. And father I
just thank you that he will um be able
to obtain another job. If it is your
will, Father God, it is your purpose and
sincere plan for his life. We thank you,
Father God, that you will open the door
for him to get another job. And if it's
for uh that business to stay afloat, we
thank you, Father God, that that will be
done. There's nothing impossible for
you. We thank you for your strength,
your mercy, your grace, Father God, for
brother Artell as he goes through this
trying time. For Clint Ives, uh there
was a seven-year-old girl that had
asthma and double pneumonia. Father God,
we just give you praise that you are
right there with this young child.
Father has double double pneumonia
and asthma.
And so, Father God, we ask that you
clear those lungs up. you clear up uh
the hearts and minds of the people that
are there with her. Calm their nerves,
calm their uh anxieties, Father God, and
allow this child to uh recover
successfully recover from the pneumonia
and from that asthma, Father God. Please
deliver her from that asthma where it
would never ever return. and for sister
Amra uh being laid off. Father God, we
thank you that you're already in the
process of working that situation out or
her job uh as far as her job is
concerned. Lord God, if it's for her to
go back, we thank you, Father, that they
will call her back and bless her even
more so coming back than she was uh
leaving. We thank you, Father God, she
asked for a MacBook Pro for freelance
projects, Father God, and a remote
position. And so, Father, nothing's too
big for you. nothing. We thank you that
as we ask, she said to ask, you shall
receive. Seek, you'll find. Knock, the
doors will be open. So, we thank you
that she's asking, seeking, and
knocking. And you're a God that not only
hear not only hears prayers, but you
answer prayers. So, thank you, Father
God, for answering your prayers, Sister
Ammer, our beloved sister Amber, and for
um Brother Terry. Thank you, Father God,
for Sister Christina.
um prayer for um her daughter Mercedes
passing clinicals. We thank you for
those clinicals, Father God. The she
would go through the testings, all that
she needs to do and she would come out
of those testings with everything that
she needs to pass, Father God, to pass.
And we just give you all the praise,
glory, and honor honor that you would
bring those things back to remembrance,
Father God, that she studied. So as she
goes through to take the test, that she
would pass. And Father God, I thank you
for um
Francis Grant, Father God, for the
two-year-old in the name of Jesus,
they're going to court. And so, Father,
you are ultimately the uh the lawyer,
the judge, uh any any the baleiff,
everyone in that courtroom, Father God,
can be used for your glory. So, we thank
you that you will touch the hearts and
minds of everyone there when they go in.
Father God, we thank you that you'll
give them the peace that surpasses all
understanding and they'll come out more
so blessed because of all the work, all
the things that you've done. It is your
will we asking to be done in Jesus'
name. And father we thank you for um
uh let's see prayer for it was major
health uh weight no inflammation for
school and it was a few other things. We
just give you praise father God for
them. uh for Sheena, for Major, it was
Major's prayer request. Father God, we
just thank you and give you all praise,
glory, and honor, Father God, for
working on their behalf. Father, you
love your children. You love for them to
come to you. You love for them to
surrender their will, their way unto you
so yours can be done. Because if we knew
what to do, what was right, Father God,
and the world wouldn't be in the
condition that is in. as they come to
you, Father God, we thank you that you
you uh teach them, guide them, give them
direction, show them your will and your
way, your purpose for and plan for their
lives. And I thank you that you work all
of those things out for them. And I just
give you the praise for doing that.
Father God, I thank you for uh the car
that that was broken down gives you an
opportunity, Father God, to either bless
that car to be restored or uh bless them
with a brand new vehicle. So, uh
Lawrence, we just thank you for bringing
this prayer request to us. to pray for
you on behalf of you and for the glory
of God. Thank you, Father God, for
working that out for Sister Lawrence and
and uh for the uh Win family grieving
the loss of a cousin. Father God, it's
hard when you lose a loved one, but we
thank you, Father God, that you stand in
the gap and you uh stand there, Father
God, where that void is now. They won't
have the cousin there with them. But
father, I pray that they understand and
know that they will soon be able to see
that cousin again. But you will fill the
gap. You will see fill the void. Father
God, you will show them who you are.
Unite with their heart and and uh put
your loving arms around them, blessing
them with your loving kindness and
tender mercies. Thank you for blessing
them through this time. And I thank you,
Father God, that when Daniel goes to
court, um, all your will will be done.
That Daniel will honor you as Lord God
and King. Daniel will surrender his
will. No matter what it is, Father God,
we thank you that Daniel will surrender
his will to yours so that your will can
be done. Your will is perfect. your
will, Father God. No one no one knows
which way or what direction to take or
what direction the court may take, but
we know that you are perfect and it will
work out according to your perfect plan
and desire. We thank you for your will
being done in Daniel when he goes to
court. Father God, we glorify and honor
you, Father, because it's going to
glorify you.
Thank you, Father God, for James the
head. He fell down uh the steps, broke
14 steps, broke three ribs, and has
sepsis. Father, he's in ICU right now.
And we thank you, Father God, that your
loving arms is around him. Father, I
pray that he knows Christ as his
personal savior. Please help him to open
his eyes at least long enough for the
priest to come in and pray with him that
he may know Jesus as his personal
savior. uh if is the thing of where he
leaves us here uh here on this planet.
Father, if it's his time to go, Father
God, we just pray that he knows Christ
as his personal savior, but strengthen
him, strengthen his family, strengthen
all who are there in the room with him,
taking care of him. Let them know that
that is your son and take good care of
him. Father, I thank you for Nikesha
experiencing discouragement. Father, uh,
demonic attacks, those are not of you.
The promises of God are yes and amen. In
your scriptures, we thank you that the
joy of the Lord will be there with her.
We thank you that she'll be strong in
the Lord and the power of your might,
Father God, that she surrenders her will
unto you for your will to be done. We
thank you, Father, from the rising of
the sun until it says she will bless
your wonderful holy name because it's
trusting. You have a your name is
trusting. We can trust in you. You never
fail, Father. to thank you for not
failing in her life. Removing these
activities, Father God, that are not of
you and in place. Restore her to health,
Father God. And that health is not only
physical, but but a spiritual health,
Father. Thank you for that spiritual
health. Um that it is the stronger man
in her life now. So, thank you, Lord
God, for her. Thank you for Barbara.
uh she's caring for an elderly uh woman
and she has she was caring for an
elderly woman and she got cancer. So,
Father, deliver her through the storm in
her life. Take her by the hand. Show her
what she it is that she needs to do, she
can do. I thank you that you're
purposedriven, God, purposely driven to
restore health, vitality, and life to
your people. And I thank you that she
will hear your voice and do all you've
called her to do.
And so, um,
there's a few more, but you know, if if
you did not hear your, uh, prayer
request,
please understand that your prayer
requests are being prayed for by us, by
the prayer team, and answered by God.
Because he not only hears again, he not
only hears your requests, your concerns,
and he can't wait to hear your prayers
and requests. He's a God of deliverance.
So just know that God is hearing from
you, hearing from us, and where two or
three are gathered in his name, he is in
the midst. God bless you.
You don't have to worry
and don't you be afraid.
Joy comes in the morning.
troubles, they don't last always.
For there's a friend in Jesus
who will wipe your tears away.
And if your heart is broken,
just lift your hands and say,
"I know that I can make it.
I know that I can stand
no matter what may come my way. My life
is in your hands.
You don't have to worry.
And don't you be afraid.
Joy comes in the morning.
troubles they don't last away.
For there's a friend in Jesus
who will wipe your tears away.
And if your heart is broken,
just lift your hands and say,
"Ooh, I know that I can make it.
I know that I can stand
no matter what may come my way.
My life is in your hand.
>> I can take it.
>> With him,
>> with him I know I can stand. No matter,
>> no matter,
>> no matter what comes my way,
my life is in your hand.
>> I know that I can make it.
>> I know.
>> I know that I can stand.
>> No matter.
>> No matter
my way,
>> my life.
My life is in your hand.
Oh, in your hand.
>> My life is in your hand.
>> Take control.
Take control.
Amen. Amen. Happy Sabbath everyone. I
want to welcome you to Living Mana's
online divine service.
And uh today uh beloved, we have a very
special word from the Lord. And so if
you are ready uh to get into the word,
I'm going to ask you to put that one in
the chat. We are getting ready to pray.
Um
and today's message
um is is dealing with the veil in the
temple. the veil in the temple and uh
we're going to see some pretty amazing
and mind-blowing things um
as the word of God is open today. So,
I'm going to invite you to pray and then
we're going to get into the word of God.
Let's go ahead and do that now.
Heavenly Father, uh we come before you,
Lord, um asking for your presence
to be with us, Lord. And as I open the
word, Lord,
I pray that uh this word will be spoken
and will bring conviction
to our hearts.
Lord, please um speak bring this message
to life
and may it impact those who hear it and
may it change us for your glory. In
Jesus name we pray. Amen. Amen.
So, um we're going to begin today's
message.
Um just with painting,
uh a picture. Uh we are going to to go
back to the Old Testament.
Uh, the children of Israel have just
been delivered from
Egypt and Moses is
given instructions
on the sanctuary that they are to build.
And different people are tasked with
different things. There are craftsmen
um all kinds of different workmen
that are
uh commissioned to work on building the
temple.
But there's one thing that I want to
focus on in this in this building and it
was the part that the women played in
this temple in this building process.
So, we're going to go to our first slide
and uh it's Exodus 35 verse 25 and 26.
And we're going to lock in on this this
this verse these verses. In Exodus 35 25
and 26, the Bible says, "And all the
women that were wisehearted
did spin with their hands and brought
that which they had spun both of blue
and of purple and of scarlet and of fine
linen." And all the women whose heart
stirred them up in wisdom spun goats
hair.
So here we have the the the women
have been tasked
with spinning this fabric
and the fabric
uh was a multi-coled
fabric. Put that put a one in the chat.
I want to make sure you are locked in.
The fabric was a multicolored fabric and
it was made by the women specifically.
Now,
why were the women uh what were the
women making
in terms of what they were spinning?
Well, the Bible doesn't tell us
specifically the women made this, but we
can we can uh uh put two and two
together and see exactly why they were
spinning this fabric. In the book of
Exodus chapter 36:35,
the Bible says, "And he made a veil of
blue and purple and scarlet and fine
twined linen with cherubams, made he it
of cunning work." So I want you to note
here that the women were the ones who
were who were making the fabric that
would ultimately go up uh in the temple
and specifically the veil of the temple.
This veil
once again was multicolored. We'll read
again here in Exodus 26:31
to33. Thou shalt make a veil of blue and
purple and scarlet and fine twine linen
of cunning work with cherubam shall it
be made. And thou shalt hang it upon
four pillars of sittwood overlaid with
gold. Their hook shall be of gold upon
the four sockets of silver.
And thou shalt hang it hang upon the
veil under the tach that th that thou
mayest bring it thither within the veil
the ark of the testimony. And the veil
shall divide unto you between the holy
and most holy. Again in Exodus 28 verse
5 and 6, they shall take gold and blue
uh and purple and scarlet and fine linen
and they shall make the ephod of gold
and of blue and purple of scarlet and
fine twine linen with cutting work. So
what we see here, what we see here is
that the women
were spinning or knitting or weaving
uh the the fabric that would make not
only the veil in the temple, but also
the priest's garments
that the priest had to wear when going
into the presence of God.
Now the cherubam are also
were also engraved if you will or or or
made upon this veil. And that is
significant because remember the veil
separated the holy from the most holy
place. And you will see
in Genesis 3 24 when Adam and Eve were
driven out of the garden, the Bible
says, "So he drove out the man and
placed at the east of the garden of Eden
cherubams and a flaming sword which
turned every way to keep the way of the
tree of life." So what we can understand
then from this veil
was that the veil was a protective
barrier
between the people between humanity and
God.
The cherubam are on this veil signifying
that what was behind the veil
was holy.
Who was behind the veil was holy.
And so
the women went to work on this veil. The
veil was multicolored. The veil had
angels upon it. Angels upon upon this
veil signifying that the presence of God
was behind the veil. That the presence
of God was protected by angels and that
this veil was a was a protective barrier
between God and man. Now, I am about to
to to jump right into the aha moment is
coming right now. And I kind of feel
sorry for the people that are that will
be coming in after this because they're
going to miss this. But I will I will
repeat it through the message, but I
need you to understand you guys that
this is absolutely mind-blowing.
Why were the women tasked
with
spinning the veil with knitting
the veil?
In Psalm 139:13,
the Bible says, "For thou has possessed
my reigns. Thou has covered me in my
mother's womb."
Now, that word covered has a special
meaning. And if I read it to you in the
ESV version, here's what it says. For
you informed my inward parts, you
knitted me together in my mother's womb.
knitted
almost as if the knitting of this of
this fabric which which by the way
represented
righteousness. The linen
was a was a was a was a picture of
righteousness. But now what we have here
is this idea
that when a person is born they are
knitted
in a woman's womb.
This veil
this veil
was something that stood between the
people and God. This veil
was something that served as a
protective barrier.
Behind that veil was divinity.
And and now all of a sudden we're
thinking, wait a minute, why were the
women tasked to make the veil?
May I share with you beloved that in
Genesis chapter 3:15, God gives a
promise to the woman in the garden,
saying something is going to be knitted
through you.
I don't know if you all caught that.
In Genesis 3:15, the Bible says, "I will
put enmity between thee and the woman,
and between thy seed and her seed, it
shall bruise thy head, and thou shalt
bruise his heel." Could it be possible
that the reason that the women were
tasked with creating this fabric was
because was because
that very veil that very veil was a
symbol of Jesus himself
whom the Bible says in Galatians 4:4 and
5, but when the fullness of time was
come, God sent forth his son made of a
woman
knitted as it were
made under the law to redeem them that
were under the law that we might receive
the adoptions of sons. Could it be
possible that the reason that the women
did the knitting was to represent the
fact that the Messiah would come born of
a woman,
knitted of a woman.
Yes. In Revelation 12:es 1-3 the Bible
tells us uh and there appeared a great
wonder in heaven a woman clothed with
the sun and un and the moon under her
feet and upon her head a crown of 12
stars and she being with child cried
travailing in birth pain to be delivered
and there appeared another wonder in
heaven and behold a great red dragon
having seven heads and 10 horns and
seven crowns upon his heads and his tail
drew the third part of the stars of
heaven and did cast him to the earth and
the dragon stood before for the woman
which was ready to be delivered
for to devour her child as soon as it
was born. And what I want you to
understand, beloved, is that the w the
the the fabric that the women were
weaving was none other than a
representation of Jesus Christ himself
who would be born
of a woman.
Knitted
Y'all put a one in the chat if you can
still hear me.
Knitted of a woman. born of a woman.
Listen again.
Remember the presence the presence hid
the glory of God. The veil hid the glory
of God so that the people were not
consumed by the glory of God. Remember
this in Exodus chapter 33. In Exodus
33:20, when when God tells Moses, "You
cannot see my face, for there shall no
man see me and live."
If anyone saw the unveiled
glory of God, the unveiled presence of
God, they would be destroyed. So in
essence, beloved, Jesus,
Jesus
became that man
in flesh that would reveal the glory of
God to us so that we could behold the
glory and yet not be consumed.
The Bible tells us in John chapter 1
verse14,
"And the word was made flesh as it were
knitted flesh and dwelt among us, and we
beheld his glory as the glory as of the
only begotten of the father, full of
grace and truth." Jesus became that man,
that veil that would allow us to see God
without being consumed. In fact, in
Matthew 17:2, the Bible tells us that
Jesus was transfigured before the
disciples and his face did shine as the
sun and his raignment was white as the
light.
They were able to to see this glory, but
because it was veiled, they were not
consumed. Jesus, beloved, was that veil.
And that's why the women were tasked
with making the veil
because it signified Jesus
being born of a woman,
coming into this world. God manifest in
the flesh but veiled so that we wouldn't
be destroyed by the glory. And now what
about the cherubam that seemed to be
hovering on this veil? You'll remember
in the book of Genesis, Jacob has a
dream and and the Bible says he dreamed
and behold a ladder set up on the earth
and the top of it reached to heaven and
behold the angels of God ascending and
descending on it.
Beloved, I need you to understand that
just as the veil was the entrance into
the presence of God, so when Jacob is is
having his dream and he sees this ladder
from earth reaching into heaven, Jesus
is that very ladder upon whom angels
were ascending and descending. And Jesus
even tells us this himself
in John 1:51. He saith unto them unto
him, "Verily, verily, I say unto you,
verily, verily, I say unto you,
hereafter you shall see heaven open, and
the angels of God ascending and
descending upon the son of man." So
Jesus, beloved, is that very veil upon
which which represents the latter
that moves us from the earth into the
very presence and glory of God.
An overlooked verse.
Oh, the women
spun the veil, weave the veil, knitted
the veil. Let's move on.
Wow. Wow. Wow. Wait a minute.
There's a reason why the women did that
task.
The women were revealing
this would be God manifest in the flesh.
The veil protecting us from being
destroyed
by the glory of God. The very ladder
through which man would have access
into the very presence of God. Now, now
that we have set the foundation,
now that we understand that this veil
represents Christ,
we can now begin to make sense of
things. When we read that as Jesus is
about to die on the cross in Matthew 27
50 and 51, the Bible says Jesus when he
had cried again with a loud voice
yielded up the ghost
and behold
the veil
of the temple was rent in twain from the
top to the bottom and the earth did
quake and the rocks rent.
Do y'all understand
what this is telling us?
In the death of Jesus,
his very flesh
was being torn on our behalf.
In the death of Jesus,
that veil being rent into
symbolized Jesus dying on our behalf,
his flesh being torn on our behalf.
What a picture. What an image.
in his death. Listen to what Hebrews
chapter 10 tells us. Having therefore,
brethren, boldness to enter into the
holiest by the blood of Jesus, by a new
and living way, which he has consecrated
for us through the veil, that is to say,
his flesh.
Wow.
Wow,
how amazing. You mean to tell me that it
is because of the death of Jesus
that veil being torn
now says guys, you can have access to
the father without being consumed.
Because of my death, my life, my death,
you can have access to the father
without being
consumed.
What a thought.
What an amazing thought. Now, now I need
to I need to share something with you.
And listen, this is the this is the the
preaching part of this message
because the Bible says that the veil was
rent into
in two.
Now, here's what I need you to
understand, beloved, because we'll read
this verse later, but the Bible says in
Revelation 19 that the fine linen is the
righteousness
of the saints.
Now, we know it's not really the
righteousness of the saints because the
saints don't have any righteousness. The
only righteousness they have is the
righteousness of Christ.
Meaning, beloved,
that the very veil that was torn
is the very veil that is our
righteousness.
Do I need to say that again?
The veil that was torn from top to
bottom. That very veil representing
Jesus Christ, representing Jesus in the
flesh, that veil was Jesus.
That veil
represents
the same covering that the priest had to
wear to enter into the presence of God.
Did y'all catch that just now?
For us
to enter into the presence of God,
we must take that veil and cover
ourselves with it.
We must take that veil,
that torn veil, that veil, rent into and
understand that that veil is the
righteousness of Christ.
Let me let me let me see if I can break
it down this way for you. Do you
remember back in the Garden of Eden when
Adam and Eve uh uh eat from the tree of
the knowledge of good and evil? Right?
And then the Bible says that they knew
that they were naked. Their eyes were
open and they knew that they were naked.
So they were now uh they now took fig
leaves and attempted to cover themselves
with their own righteousness partially
to hide themselves from the presence and
gaze of God.
They were embarrassed. They were
ashamed.
And so when God comes to the garden, the
Bible says in Exodus 3:27, "And the eyes
of them both were opened and they knew
that they were naked and they sewed fig
leaves together and made themselves
aprons." So they tried to cover their
their own wickedness, their own sins,
their own sinful sinfulness with fig
leaves.
And so God comes to the garden and he's
like, "Yeah, that those fig leaves
aren't going to work. That's not going
to work. Fig leaves, you you're not
going to be able to stand in my presence
with fig leaves." And so what does he
do? The Bible says in Genesis 3 21,
"Unto Adam also and to his wife did the
Lord God make coats of skins and clothe
them.
They took the flesh
of an animal
and clothed Adam and Eve.
When the women in the sanctuary are
weaving this fabric, this this fabric
that is multicolored. Remember that?
Remember that? Remember that y'all
multicolored.
A multicolored
garment robe. That multicolored robe
represented
righteousness.
And and it is this multicolored robe
that that served also as the veil
separating between the people and God.
And we've just learned that that that
fabric that veil was literally symbolic
of Jesus himself.
So that when he dies, the veil is rent.
Meaning Jesus's flesh has been torn for
you. Jesus's robe
has been torn for you. Why? Why has the
robe been torn? Why has the veil been
torn? Oh, that torn veil which
represents the righteousness of Christ
is supposed to cover us.
This is why the Bible says in Galatians
3:27, "For as many of you as have been
baptized into Christ have put on
Christ."
They've put on
Christ.
Do y'all see this?
They have put on Christ. They have put
on
Jesus.
They have put him
on the robe. The the veil has been put
on.
Are Are y'all catching this?
Are y'all understanding
what is going on
beloved?
Watch this. Do you remember how in the
Old Testament, let me let me let me show
you again. Let's go back to the screen.
Exodus chapter 28:43.
And they shall be upon Aaron and upon
his sons, talking about the garments.
And when they come into the tabernacle
of the congregation, or where they come
near to the altar to minister in the
holy place, that they bear not iniquity
and die, it shall be a statute forever
unto him and a seed after him. To get
into the presence of God, you've got to
be covered with the righteousness of
God.
You remember, you remember there was a
story, there was a story in the Old
Testament of of a man by the name of
Jacob. Yeah, remember that story. And
Jacob had 12 sons. And one of his sons,
one of his sons,
one of his sons, Joseph, the Bible says,
let's read it. Genesis 37:3, "Now Israel
loved Joseph more than all his children,
because he was a son of his old age, and
he made him a coat
of many colors.
He made him a coat of many colors.
Wow.
Wow. Wow. Wow. Listen to me. May I
suggest to you, beloved, and and this is
my this is my pastoral speak. Okay? The
Bible doesn't say this particular, but I
but I just want to use it as an example.
Okay? The veil was rent in two. If the
veil represents the righteousness of
Christ, I want you to focus.
I want you to to uh I want you to to to
think with me, right? If the veil
represents the righteousness of Christ
and it's rent in two,
could it be possible, beloved, could we
connect the veil being rent in two with
the fact that there are two aspects
to the righteousness
of Christ.
You see beloved, there is Christ's
imputed
righteousness and Christ's imparted
righteousness.
And beloved, may I suggest to you that
in order to enter into the presence of
God, we've got to be covered
with both aspects of the robe.
Y'all put a five in the chat if you
understand what I'm saying. We are to be
covered. The veil was rent in twain. If
the veil represents the righteousness of
Christ, can we then imagine that
righteousness as the imputed and
imparted righteousness of Christ?
What is the imputed righteousness of
Christ? It is when Christ's
righteousness covers us,
covers our past, is imputed to us.
The Bible says, "While we were yet
sinners, he died for us." I and I need I
want to build this out for you through
the story of Joseph because you'll
remember that the brothers did not like
Joseph. And in fact, they you the story
goes on that they that they are that
they throw Joseph in a pit, right? And
you remember what they did with his
coat. I want you to watch this. They
they take his coat, right? And they know
that Joseph is beloved of the father. So
watch what happens in Genesis 37.
Genesis 37:31. The Bible says, "And they
took Joseph's coat."
man.
They took Joseph's coat and killed a kid
of the goats and dipped the coat in the
blood. You guys, they don't even realize
what they in their wickedness,
they are actually
fulfilling Bible prophecy without even
knowing it. They take the coat and dip
it in blood, wash it as it were in
blood.
And they sent the coat.
They sent the coat of many colors. And
they brought it to the father.
They brought it to the father. The text
says their father.
But I need you to I need you to see the
double language, the double h uh
symbolism that I'm trying to show you
right now. They dipped the blood. Hey,
your son is dead. And here is the
evidence. And the Bible says they said
this we have found now whether it be thy
son's code or no or no now whether it be
thy son's code or no. and he knew it and
he said, "It is my son's coat. An evil
beast has devoured him." Joseph is
without doubt rent in pieces.
Now, I need y'all to see something, you
guys.
This is this is mindblowing what I'm
about to tell you
because do y'all see what happens here?
How many of you see what happens here?
Watch this. Let me go to the next verse
very quickly. Read it. Then I'm going to
come back and comment. And Jacob rent
his clothes and put sackcloth upon his
loins and mourned for his son many days.
And all his sons and all his daughters
rose up to comfort him. But he refused
to be comforted. And he said,"For I will
go down into the grave unto my son
mourning." Thus his father wept for him.
Do you know? Do you see what Joseph's
coat did
for the brothers?
Y'all put a seven in the chat. Put a one
in the chat if you don't see. Put a
seven in the chat if you do see. I I I
just want to test this out here. Put a
seven in the chat if you see what
Joseph's coat dipped in blood did for
his brothers.
Because when his brothers come with the
with a coat
dipped in blood,
I need you to understand that when the
father sees that coat, he is not angry
at his other sons.
His
entire concern is for his his son. His
son that has died, the the veil, the
coat of many colors show signs that he
is dead. And the brothers, though they
do not deserve it, the ra they are
protected from the wrath of the father
by presenting the son's coat to the
father.
Oh wow, y'all.
there. The coat
of many colors dipped in blood covered
the brother's
sin.
Wow.
When the father looks at the coat, he is
not like, "What have you done?" He is
like, "My son, my son, my son." and he's
weeping for his son. Do we ever stop to
think about what the father feels as he
sees the torn veil?
Listen to me, y'all. He is not angry.
The goodness of God, y'all.
The goodness of God. He is not angry
with the people that kill his son. He
simply looks at the torn veil and says,
"My son
has been taken by a wild beast.
Sin did this to my son. Sin did this to
my son. My son. My son. My son. My son."
And the brothers,
the brothers are cover. their sin
is covered
by the veil.
And you know, I the Bible doesn't say
this. The Bible doesn't say this, but I
imagine that they would have had to put
rips in Joseph's coat.
If a wild beast got him,
then how come there's no tears
in the coat?
Now, now that that is just that is just
my assumption that they probably put
rips in the coat,
which would make sense, but I need you
to understand how it is almost as as if
they received cover for their sin. What
is imputed righteousness? Let me let me
show you Romans chapter 4. Romans
chapter 4 7 and 8. Blessed are they
whose iniquities are forgiven and whose
sins are covered. Blessed is the man to
whom the Lord will not impute
sin.
Wow.
Wow. You guys. Wow. Wow. Wow. Wow.
Wow. This is absolutely amazing.
The coat, Joseph's coat covered his
brother's
sins.
An image, a a reflection,
a shadow of what the imputed
righteousness of Christ does for us.
It covers us.
It says, "I forgive you for all that you
have done in the past. I cover you. You
are covered in my blood. You're covered
in my bloodstained robe. You're covered
by that veil that was rent into one of
those one of those pieces of the veil
represent the imputed
righteousness of if the veil represents
the righteousness of Christ, then let's
just say for our for our example of
teaching that one of those pieces is the
imputed
righteousness of Christ.
And then what about the imparted
righteousness of Christ? What about that
imparted righteousness of Christ? And
yes, the brothers were beasts. The
brothers were the beasts
that did that thing to that robe. But
you know what happened? I I listen
y'all.
Uh
it is it is it is an amazing thing what
godly sorrow can do
because as the as the brothers
have escaped punishment that they
rightly deserved.
Can you imagine the godly sorrow?
They're struggling in their walk.
They're struggling.
But
what they saw
in the father's love for the son and
their own guilt in causing a tear
between father and son, a separation
between father and son.
Something about that changed them. It
wasn't in a day. It wasn't in two days.
Yeah. They they they were covered from
their they were covered in their sins
immediately soon as they saw the coat.
Father didn't think them wasn't like I
blame you. It his focus was on the torn
coat. His focus was on the son that he
lost.
And so the brothers, they're not even
condemned for what they actually did.
But beloved, in that moment, they're
like, "How how could we have done such a
thing? How could we have caused the
father such pain? How could we have
caused the separation of father and son?
How could we have played a role in this?
How could we have done this?" And the
added intensity of guilt.
We don't deserve this. We don't deserve
a free pass with the father.
I mean, can you imagine the father is
now treating his other sons? Again, the
Bible doesn't say this, but you can just
imagine the father must be like, I
definitely got to watch out now for my
other sons. I don't the pain of lo
losing Joseph was like this. I don't
want to lose any of my other sons. So
now, yeah, I may have been favor. I may
have been playing favorites with Joseph,
but now now I just got to really lock in
on these other sons and take care of
them and whatever I need to do to keep
them alive cuz I don't want to see any.
You can imagine that his love for his
other sons may have intensified.
He may have even wrestled with God like
why was I favor? What you know, I love
Joseph. Why did I favor? Maybe I was
wrong in treating these other brothers,
you know, these other sons. I mean, just
think about all we're just thinking,
right? The the the humanity of it all.
And so, just imagine that he's now
treating his sons with with much more
love and much more, you know, hey, I I
love you all and don't think that I that
I don't. And you can imagine what that
kind of love and mercy and forgiveness
even when they knew they did not deserve
it.
What a change that must have caused in
them. And we know they changed.
We know that they had to have changed
because when those many years pass by
and they and they are run into Joseph
again and do not know that it is him and
they are put through this test and
they're like we are not leaving our
little brother. No way take us. You can
see that there has been some kind of
imparted
some kind of process in which the people
that they were before the quote
incidents has been chain they're new
people now
they're new people now so that when
Joseph finally reveals himself hey I am
Joseph your brother and they all come to
re realization of everything that has
gone on. I want you to check out how
this how the story concludes. Watch
this, y'all. In Genesis 45-22,
45:22,
to all of them he gave each man.
We could just stop right there, y'all.
The bloody coat
gave them cover for their sins,
covered their past sins.
But now when when they have shown we've
changed, they get change of Raymond
again.
Could it be possible, beloved, that in
that code of many colors? in this veil
of many colors.
That veil being rent for us
was to say, "Hey priests,
I want you to be kings and priests with
me. So, I'm going to give you
the garments
that the priests need to wear as they
come in to minister
before me.
Wow.
Wow. Wow. Wow.
It kind of reminds me of Zechariah
chapter 3:4
where where the Bible says he the angel
of the Lord said spake unto those that
stood before him saying take away the
filthy garments from him
that is Joshua
and said unto him behold I have caused
thy iniquity to pass from thee
and I will give I will clothe thee with
change of raignment
Revelation 19:8 to her was granted that
she should be arrayed in fine linen,
clean and white. For the fine linen is
the righteousness of the saints.
You guys, this is absolutely powerful.
Come on, this is our closing slide.
Well, almost closing. Almost closing.
But come back to the screen for a
moment.
You remember right that in this story of
of Joseph, right, that he goes to Egypt
and and by the time the story gets to
its ending, Joseph has been elevated to
the right hand of Pharaoh.
So in essence, we can say
that God had sent Joseph ahead of his
brothers to prepare a place for them.
To prepare a place for them. Remember in
Genesis 41 41, Pharaoh said unto Joseph,
"See, I have set thee over all the land
of Egypt." And Pharaoh took off his ring
from his hand, and put it on Joseph's
hand, and arrayed him in vestures of
fine linen. Fine linen. Fine linen. F I
didn't even see that, y'all. This is
accidental.
This is accidental.
arrayed him investors of fine linen and
put a gold chain about his neck and made
him to ride in the second chariot which
he had and they cried before him bow the
knee and he made him ruler over all the
land of Egypt. And what did Joseph say
in verse 7? God sent me before you to
preserve you a posterity in the earth
and to save your lives by a great
deliverance. Do you realize that God
sent Jesus
ahead of us
so that he could prepare a place for us?
Yes. Yes. Yes. I go to prepare a place
for you. Come on. That two more verses.
who being the brightness of his glory
and the express image of his person and
upholding all things by the word of his
power. When he had by himself purged our
sins, that rent veil, y'all, that rent
veil was torn
was torn to provide us the clothing
necessary to enter the presence
of the majesty on high.
John 14 John 14 2 and 3 in my father's
house are many mansions if it were not
so I would have told you I go to prepare
a place for you and if I go to prepare a
place for you I will come again and
receive you unto myself that where I am
there you may be also beloved I need you
to understand
that the only way we get to that place
then is if we now
Take that rent veil,
the flesh of Jesus, the person of Jesus,
the righteousness of Jesus, and cover
ourselves
with the imputed robe of his
righteousness
and the imparted robe of his
righteousness.
And as we understand,
as we understand
the love of the father for the son
that when he saw that ripped veil,
there was no anger
towards us.
It was simply my son, my son.
And in that torn veil, in that torn veil
of many colors, that was the name of the
sermon. I told you the veil was only
half, but if I told you veil of many
colors, y'all would have started making
the connections. I need you to wait to
to to get the connection.
In that torn
veil of many colors
is both the imputed righteousness of
Christ and the imparted righteousness of
Christ. When we see the love of father
for son and know that we deserved
death
but in it
we only see the love of a father for his
son.
Wow.
that godly sorrow,
that sense of of guilt for what we have
done, knowing I do not deserve to be
forgiven.
And yet that blood stained robe,
covered me.
Wow.
Wow. Wow. Wow.
I know I said it was the last verse, but
I just need to read Revelation 19:8
again. That's our closing verse. We
We're just going to close with that. To
her was granted that she should be
arrayed in fine linen, clean and white,
for the fine linen is the righteousness
of the saints. Do you I love that it was
the women who weaved the garment.
And one of the last verses in the Bible
say,
in essence, it's telling us the garment
that you weaved,
woman,
church.
Remember, it was the church that was
pregnant with Christ. That woman clothed
with the sun, the moon under her feet,
pregnant with the sun.
That very garment you weaved. And I, you
know, I can't I can't help but think
about Jesus being born and the Bible
says him being wrapped in swaddling
clothes,
the righteousness,
that righteousness, that very robe
is given back to the woman.
Cover yourself with this.
It's not your righteousness.
It's Christ's righteousness.
And today, I want to appeal to you by
simply asking you,
how many of you,
how many of you would like to tail that
veil,
to take that veil that was rent for you?
Maybe have, maybe you're just like,
whoa, the veil in the temple, man,
that's a that's what what a story. But I
never knew I was supposed to put that
veil on.
I never knew that that veil was the
imputed and imparted righteousness of
Christ.
Lord, help me to cover help me to cover
myself with that veil, not fig leaves,
with that veil.
And may the love that I see for the
father to the son and the knowledge
that I do not deserve forgiveness and
yet I got it. His death remove the
father's wrath towards us as sons
to focus on the death of his son.
May that realization
produce in us the imparted righteousness
of Christ. Heavenly Father,
as your people are putting that one in
the chat saying, "Yes, Lord, that is me.
Please help me to receive the imputed
and imparted righteousness of Christ.
Help me to receive
that robe dipped in blood,
washed in blood.
Help me to receive the righteousness of
Christ.
Lord, please change our lives. Help us
to understand that it is not by our own
power that we change, but by the
realization of the great sorrow
we have caused the Godhead,
the father
in losing his son
at the cross.
that that same son has ascended to the
right hand of heaven to prepare a place
where we might enter in through that
ladder, through that veil into the
presence of God,
clothed
with the righteousness of Christ.
We don't deserve it. But may that
realization
draw out of us a love
that cannot be quenched,
a righteousness
that cannot be removed.
This we pray in Jesus name. Amen. And
amen.
May God bless you all as you meditate
upon this message, as you contemplate
this message. Um, we're going to go
ahead and put this last slide on the
screen so that if you would like a copy
of these sermon notes, if you want to
follow us on social media, uh, if you
want to connect with Living Mana, if you
have prayer requests or if you have a
request to be baptized, all the
information is there. Uh we will also
put in the link um we will also put in
the in the in the chat the link to join
us um for our afterglow uh through
mighty networks. Um again may God bless
you and may God keep you uh and may God
draw you closer to him and to his
presence. Amen.
Thank you for joining us today. If this
is your first time worshiping with us,
please check out our website at
livingmana.urch.
We are not just here for Sabbath
service. We have weekly programming too
that covers mental health, physical
health, weekly prayer service, financial
health, and proving the existence of
God. It is our desire that our
programming will continue to bless you.
Please continue to pray for us as we
fulfill God's mission to go into all the
world with the gospel of Jesus Christ.